<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VINODH'S NOTES</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/</link><description>Mind Blogging</description><atom:link href="https://vinotes.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com"&gt;Vinodh MJ Human&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 22:17:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>പയ്യന്റെ ചിത്രം പത്രത്തിൽ </title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/chitrampathrathil/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
ഇളം കാറ്റ്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഒരു കൈയിൽ കണ്ണട, മറുകൈയിൽ പത്രം. അച്ഛൻ വരാന്തയിലേക്ക് വന്നു. ഒറ്റമുണ്ട്, വെള്ള ബനിയൻ,
ആവശ്യത്തിലധികം ഭസ്മക്കുറി. ആകെമൊത്തം ധവളാഭം. കണ്ണടയിട്ട് കസേരയിലിരുന്നു. എന്നിട്ട് പത്രത്തിന്റെ
മേൽത്തലപ്പിലൂടെ മുറ്റത്തേക്ക് നോക്കി. അമ്മ പൂജയ്ക്ക് പൂപറിക്കുകയാണ്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; : ഭവതി പൂപറിക്കുകയാണെന്ന് കണ്ടറിയുന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അമ്മ&lt;/b&gt; : ഹോംസിന്റെ നിരുപമമായ വീക്ഷണബുദ്ധിയെ ഇന്ന് വീണ്ടും ഞാൻ അഭിനന്ദിക്കുന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; : നന്ദി പറയേണ്ട ഈ അവസരത്തിൽ ഇങ്ങനെ ചൊല്ലുന്നത് ശരിതന്നെയോ എന്നറിയില്ല.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അമ്മ&lt;/b&gt; : ശരിയല്ല.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; : എങ്കിലും…, പത്രവും ചായയും. അതല്ലേ കേരളീയരുടെ മൗലികാവകാശം? പത്രവായനേന തേയിലപാനീയനേന എന്നല്ലേ ഗുരുവാക്യം.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അമ്മ&lt;/b&gt; : രാവിലെതന്നെ വേണോ ലോ-കീ ഗീർവാണം? ഭഗവാന് പുഷ്പ്പാർച്ചന, ശേഷം ഭർത്താവിന് ചായ.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; : ദൈവത്തിന് പൂകൊടുക്കാൻ വേറെ എത്രയോ മഹിളകൾ ഈ നാട്ടിലുണ്ട്. എനിക്ക് ചായ തരാൻ നീ മാത്രമല്ലേയുള്ളു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അമ്മ&lt;/b&gt; : അറിഞ്ഞതിൽ വളരെ സന്തോഷം.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; : "ദാറ്റ് വാസ് എ ഗുഡ് വൺ".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;(അച്ഛൻ വായന തുടരുന്നു. അമ്മ അകത്തേക്ക് പോകുന്നു.)&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; : അതേ…
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അമ്മ&lt;/b&gt; : ദാ വരുന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; : ചായ വേണ്ട. ഒന്നിങ്ങോട്ടു വരൂ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;(ഭയങ്കര നിശബ്ദ. പിന്നെ കാലൊച്ച.)&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അമ്മ&lt;/b&gt; :  "ചന്ദ്രനിലും ഗുരുത്വാകർഷണം, മലയാളിക്കിന്നു ചായ വേണ്ട", എന്നാണോ പ്രധാനവാർത്ത.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അച്ഛൻ (പത്രം നീട്ടികൊണ്ട് ) : ഹ്രസ്വഹാസ്യം മതിയാകൂ, എന്നിട്ടിത് നോക്കു. അറിയോ ഇയാളെ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അമ്മ&lt;/b&gt; : ഇത്…
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; : അതെ, നമ്മുടെ മോൻ തന്നെ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അമ്മ&lt;/b&gt; : ഇവനെങ്ങനെ…
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; : വായിക്കാം. കേട്ടോളൂ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
പാലക്കാട് : പേരുവെളിപ്പെടുത്താനാഗ്രഹിക്കാത്ത പാലക്കാട്ടുകാരൻ പയ്യൻ അതീവ സുന്ദരനാണെങ്കിലും,
മാതാപിതാക്കളുടെ സന്തോഷം ആഗ്രഹിക്കുന്നവനാണ്. സ്വന്തം ചിത്രം പത്രത്തിൽ കൊടുക്കാനുണ്ടായ സാഹചര്യം പയ്യൻ
ലളിതമായി വിവരിക്കുന്നു. കഴിഞ്ഞാഴ്ച്ചയാണ് യൂണിവേഴ്സിറ്റി പരീക്ഷാഫലം വന്നത്. അതേ ആഴ്ചതന്നെയാണ്
ചേച്ചിയുടെ റാങ്ക് വിവരവും, ഫോട്ടോയും പത്രത്തിൽ വന്നത്. ലഡ്ഡു ഭക്ഷിക്കുന്നതിനിടയിൽ പയ്യനേയും,
പത്രത്തേയും, ചിത്രത്തെയും ഒരേവാക്യത്തിൽ അച്ഛനമ്മമാർ പ്രയോഗിച്ചു. പയ്യനിനിയും പല പരീക്ഷകൾ
പാസാവാനിരിക്കുന്നതേയുള്ളു. എങ്കിലും അവരുടെ ആഗ്രഹസാഫല്യത്തിന് വേണ്ടി അല്പം പ്രയത്നിക്കണമെന്ന് പയ്യന്
തോന്നി. അതിനുവേണ്ടി എന്നത്തേയുംപോലെ പയ്യൻ അമ്മയുടെ പേഴ്സിൽ നിന്നും അമ്മയറിയാതെ രൂപ കടം
വാങ്ങി. അമ്മേ, അഭിപ്രായസ്വാതന്ത്രത്തിനിന്നു നമ്മുടെ നാട്ടിൽ വലിയ വിലകൊടുകേണ്ടതുണ്ടെന്ന് ഞാൻ മനസിലാക്കുന്നു. ഇനിയും
കുറേ എഴുതണം എന്നുണ്ട്, പക്ഷേ ഫോട്ടോയുടെ വലിപ്പം കുറയ്‌ക്കേണ്ടിവരും എന്ന് ഈ ഉണ്ടക്കണ്ണൻ പറഞ്ഞത് കൊണ്ട്
നിർത്തുന്നു . ഇൻക്വിലാബ്.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അമ്മ&lt;/b&gt; : ഇവന്റെ കാര്യത്തിൽ നമുക്ക് കുറച്ചുകൂടെ സൂക്ഷിക്കാമായിരുന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;അച്ഛൻ&lt;/b&gt; :
"പലാനാം പലവിധാനാം, 
ബഹ്വാനാം ബഹുവിധാനാം,  
അതിലൊരു വിധാനാം".
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>comedy</category><category>payyan</category><category>satire</category><category>പയ്യൻ</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/chitrampathrathil/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 10:46:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Subscribe</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/subscribe/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
വിനോട്ടിസിന്റെ വരിക്കാരാകുവാൻ &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com?subject=Subscribe%20to%20Vinotes&amp;amp;body=Cheers"&gt;ഇവിടെ&lt;/a&gt; ഞെക്കുക. അത് നിങ്ങളുടെ ഇമെയിൽ ആപ്പ് തുറക്കും, അതിൽ
സെൻട് അമർത്തുക. നന്ദി.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Please click &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com?subject=Subscribe%20to%20Vinotes&amp;amp;body=Cheers"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe to Vinotes. Clicking on the link will open your default
mail application. On the pre-filled mail, please click send. Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/subscribe/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 18:00:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ചിന്താമഗ്നനായി</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/payyanchinthamagnanayi/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;വായന സമയം : 2 മിനിറ്റ്&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
മനസ്സിന്റെ സന്തുലിതയെ തകർക്കാൻ വിശപ്പിനു സാധിക്കും. ഇതല്ല, വേറെന്തോ എഴുതാനാണ്
ഉദ്ദേശിച്ചത്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
മനസൊരു കുളമാണെന്ന് കരുതി. അതിലേക്കു നീട്ടി എറിഞ്ഞ ഒരു പരന്ന കല്ല് പോലെ ആശയം തെന്നി തെന്നി ദൂരെ
മറയുന്നു. പക്ഷേ അതൊരിക്കലും അക്കരെയെത്തുന്നില്ല. ജലാശയത്തിനു നടുവിൽ ആശയത്തിന്റെ പയനം
പര്യവസാനിക്കുന്നു. പിന്നീട് എപ്പോഴോ ഒരു പഴയ ഓർമ്മ കൊളുത്തിയ പുതിയ ആവേശത്തിൽ, ആ ജലാശയത്തിലേക്കു
നാം എടുത്തു ചാടുന്നു. മുങ്ങി നീന്തി ആശയത്തെ പുറത്തു കൊണ്ടുവരാൻ ശ്രമിക്കുന്നു. നീന്തി നീന്തി കുളത്തിന്റെ
നടുവിലെത്തുമ്പോൾ, അവിടെ ഒരു ആശയദ്വീപ്! ചെറിയ പരന്ന കല്ലുകൾ കൊണ്ട് രൂപപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്ന ഒരു
അതിശയദ്വീപ്. ഓരോ കല്ലിലും തന്റെ കയ്യൊപ്പ് പതിഞ്ഞിരിക്കുന്നു. അതുകണ്ട് ആദ്യം ഒന്ന് അന്ധാളിക്കുന്നു, ഞാൻ
താൻ തന്നെയോ ഇത് എന്ന് ചിന്തിച്ച്‌ ഉറ്റുനോക്കുന്നു. വലിച്ചെറിഞ്ഞ ആശയങ്ങളുടെ ഇടയിൽ നിന്നും ഒരു ചെറുപുളകം
കുളിർപ്രവാഹത്തിലൂടെ തന്നെ തലോടുന്നു. മന്ദഹാസപുഞ്ചിരി ചുണ്ടിൽ വ്യാപിക്കുന്നു. സ്വാഭിമാനം
രോമാഞ്ചമണിയിക്കുന്നു. ആശയത്തെ വീണ്ടും ഉപേക്ഷിച്ച്, വികാരം മാത്രം ഉൾക്കൊണ്ട് ഉപരിതലത്തിലേക്ക്
ഉദിച്ചുയരുന്നു. വിടർന്ന ചുണ്ടുകളിലൂടെ ഒരു ചോദ്യം, ഇനി എന്ത്?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഇതല്ല, വേറെന്തോ എഴുതാനാണ് ഉദ്ദേശിച്ചത്. എന്തായാലും അടുക്കള വരെ ഒന്ന് പോയി നോക്കാം.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>payyan</category><category>പയ്യൻ</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/payyanchinthamagnanayi/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:46:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Acting</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/acting/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Curiouser and Curiouser gets life at every random decision we make. I was
labouring under the delusion that by not bothering to give a try at something,
one was assured to be bad at it. If these words were short and catchy, it would
have become my motto. Does that make any sense? Life is Schrodinger's cat all
over again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Bit of background, I moved to a different country to pursue the ever elusive
higher education. Call it the autumn madness, I enrolled for an audition at the
University's drama society. My first audition. All I wanted was to experience
the process, and to mildly irritate the panel with uncouth improvisations. I
auditioned for the role of Guy Tree, a homeless person carelessly wandering into
a farm owned by two sisters. The sisters had inherited the farm from their
recently deceased parents. Sisters adopts Guy Tree into their farm and
household, and he helps them in managing the farm. I was asked to deliver a
monologue of Guy Tree reminiscing his past; living in a busy city with his
parents, and him wanting peace and quiet. When he eventually reach the farm
which is extraordinarily quiet, he finds the silence intolerable. Done. We will
let you know in couple of days. Two days later, I got a recall from the team.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Having no expectations is perhaps our greatest courage to attempt out of the
ordinary deeds. And when someone identifies the petite potential in us, that
discovery becomes the worst form of scaremongering. I was nervous going into the
recall auditions because, around 80 members auditioned for this in the first
round. Majority of them belonged to related fields of study, like Literature,
Drama Studies, Gender Studies, Film Studies etc. I was an Electrical
Engineer. Regardless of the outcome, I convinced myself to enjoy the experience.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ben, brother of the two sisters running the farm comes into the play. Freddie
played Ben's character. I played Guy Tree. A lengthy conversation between the
generally insecure yet extroverted Ben, and the optimistic but introverted Guy
was to be enacted for the recall auditions. After practising couple of times, we
went into the audition room. The panel were ready when we were ready. For the
fifteen minutes that I acted as Guy Tree, I saw only Ben in Freddie's form and
an imaginary Ewe about to give birth in the corner of the room. The panel
members were invisible to me. I was Guy Tree for that short period. I did not
get the part, but I definitely enjoyed the experience.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So, what I wanted to say was : "Do it".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Many Peace.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/acting/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 18:00:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Love</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/love/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
How can it be put into words?&lt;br&gt;
For love itself is a word, borrowed.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/love/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 23:15:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Leprechaun</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/leprechaun/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;div class="org-center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://vinotes.github.io/galleries/rainbow.JPG" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Ooh, maybe we should look for the pot of gold at the end of it".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Oh my god! Leprechauns. Have you not heard about Leprechauns?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Of course not.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
According to Irish folklore, Leprechauns are cunning supernatural creatures.
They sport a red beard, green coat and a hat. Full time cobblers, and part time
pranksters, they are notorious for their practical jokes on the gullible.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What has it to do with a rainbow?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Once upon a time, there lived a poor farmer with his wife. When they pulled the
very last carrot from their farm, found a Leprechaun dangling at the end of
it. In exchange for its release, the Leprechaun granted them one wish. The
couple took a while to decide on the wish, and started to list out all the
things they wanted in life. Leprechaun identified this as a symptom of greed,
and played a cruel prank on the poor farmers. It said, maybe the pot of gold at
the end of the rainbow will solve all your problems. The couple went searching
after the elusive pot of gold. Moral(s) of the story: Be careful what you wish
for, You only get what you deserve, Success through shortcuts will not last
longer, etc.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Oh, wait. In Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire, the Irish National Quidditch
team's mascots were Leprechauns, weren't they?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Yes, indeed they were.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Bloody hell.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Would you like to hear about St. Patrick's day celebrations in Ireland?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
No, thank you, I need to re-read the fourth book, cheers!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="org-center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://vinotes.github.io/galleries/leprechaun.png" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/leprechaun/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 19:28:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Police Chase</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/policechase/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Midnight, Manchester.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
An otherwise remarkably quiet residential area was woken up by blaring sirens of
what was unmistakably police cars. Peeped through the window to witness a
chase. Unidentified grey car speedily approaching a junction; followed by three
police cars with dancing lights and high-pitched sirens. Grey car trying to
escape into a narrow alleyway only to be stopped by barricades. That path was
clearly reserved for pedestrians supporting climate change. Grey car rammed into
one of the barricades, and that was enough for the police cars to corner it. The
Hero/Villain(just a matter of perspective isn't it?) abandoned the car and ran
for it. Officers followed him. Sirens and dancing light remained in the
junction.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Seven minutes later…
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Villain/Hero was now handcuffed and being pushed back towards the junction. The
police searched him to find nothing on him. Searched the grey car and the
officer's hand was reassuringly empty. Another officer asked the Villain/Hero,
"The car is stolen innit?". Officer walked towards the license plate and pulled
it to find another license plate underneath it. "Fornicating hell, you're right",
shouted somebody. The Villain/Thief was arrested and carried away in his
silence. Sirens went off, lights out, grey car was towed away. Remarkably quiet
residential area went back to sleep. I need to get some sleep as well. Tickets
for the new James Bond movie is already booked for tomorrow night show. Well, I
will watch it anyway.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Many Peace.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/policechase/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 05:50:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Yellow Balloon</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/yellow-balloon/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The night, soothingly quiet, Poet awoke in her bed.&lt;br&gt;
Eyes wide, a story unsaid, raging in her head.&lt;br&gt;
She opened her book and started scribbling away,&lt;br&gt;
With hope that the memory of her dream would stay.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Lying on a hammock she thought,&lt;br&gt;
About a piquant dream she caught.&lt;br&gt;
An unsaid story that she must tell,&lt;br&gt;
But out of her mind it suddenly fell.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It was about a familiar young girl,&lt;br&gt;
Who wore a necklace made of pearl.&lt;br&gt;
Ah..! that curious world inside a crystal bowl,&lt;br&gt;
And indeed the villain who made the story whole!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Enter Villain, with a yellow balloon in his hand,&lt;br&gt;
Seven feet tall, skinny lad was all tanned.&lt;br&gt;
With him he brought his own music band,&lt;br&gt;
Popular songs that it played were all banned.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Yellow balloon hovered above his head like a halo,&lt;br&gt;
Her eyes twinkled as she went to say hello.&lt;br&gt;
Will you give me that yellow balloon I crave?&lt;br&gt;
Quid pro quo, the pearl necklace, that I will take to my grave.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The necklace? no, no!&lt;br&gt;
Oh dear, why is that so?&lt;br&gt;
Because you’re the villain in this story!&lt;br&gt;
Yes, but villains are also part of history.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
No, I know, villains always lose in the end.&lt;br&gt;
Right you are! Here, take the balloon my friend.&lt;br&gt;
As she reached out for the balloon, he let it fly,&lt;br&gt;
Ha-ha! where's the fun in not letting it touch the sky.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
She woke up with a start, still lying on her hammock,&lt;br&gt;
The pearl necklace was planted safely on her neck.&lt;br&gt;
Opened her book and started scribbling away,&lt;br&gt;
With hope that the memory of her dream would stay.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The night, soothingly quiet, is coming to its end,&lt;br&gt;
The poet now stood in her balcony facing the cold wind.&lt;br&gt;
Words rhyming on her book, Pearls shining on her neck,&lt;br&gt;
As she smiled at an yellow balloon that dawned up in the sky.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/yellow-balloon/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>പയ്യൻ പത്രവായന നിർത്തി</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/pathra-vayana/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
പയ്യൻ പത്രവായന നിർത്തി. വേറൊന്നും കൊണ്ടല്ല, ഇനി അതിന്റെയാവശ്യം ഇല്ലെന്ന് പയ്യന്
തോന്നി. എന്നത്തേയും പോലെ കാലത്ത് പത്രം വായിക്കാൻ വരാന്തയിലേക്ക് പോയ വാർത്താത്യാഗ്രഹിയായ പയ്യനെ
വരവേറ്റത് &lt;i&gt;അൺകിളും ആൺട്ടിയുമാണ്.&lt;/i&gt; ചുമരിൽ ചേർത്തിയിട്ടിരുന്ന സോഫാകസേര വലിച്ചു ഫാനിനു താഴെയിട്ട്
അൺകിളും, ചുമരിനോട് ചേർന്ന് തന്നെ ഇരുന്ന് ആൺട്ടിയും പയ്യനെ നോക്കി. കണ്ടയുടനെ പുളിയുറുമ്പിന്റെ കടികൊണ്ട
അണ്ണാന്റെ ശബ്ദത്തിൽ ആൺട്ടി അലറി:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;'ഏതാണീ ഭ്രാന്തൻ !!!'&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ആൺട്ടി റെട്ടോറിക്കിന് തിരികൊളുത്തിയതാണെന്ന് മനസ്സിലാക്കിയ പയ്യൻ മൊസൈക് കളത്തിൽ നിന്നുകൊണ്ട്
മൗനാവതാരമെടുത്തു. പൊരി, കതിനയുടെ മൂട്ടിൽ തട്ടിയ ക്ഷണം അൺകിൾ പൊട്ടിത്തെറിച്ചു:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;'അവന്റെ ഒരു താടിയും മുടിയും. എന്ത് വൃത്തികെട്ട കോലമാണിത് !!!'&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കമ്മ്യൂണിസ്റ്റ് സർക്കാരിന്റെ പശുക്കളിൽ നിന്നും കറന്നെടുത്ത പാലിൽ കലക്കിയ ക്യാപിറ്റലിസത്തിന്റെ കൊഴുത്ത
ഹോർലിക്‌സ് ദ്രാവകം "സ്റ്റീൽ ഗ്ലാസ്സിന്റെ" രൂപത്തിൽ മേശപ്പുറത്തു വച്ചുകൊണ്ടു അൺകിൾ അടുക്കള നോക്കി അലറി:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;'എന്റെ ദാക്ഷായണി, നീ ഇത് കാണുന്നില്ലേ ?'&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അടുക്കളയിൽ നിന്നും അമ്മ പാഞ്ഞെത്തി. പരിഭ്രാന്തി, ആകാംഷ, മുതലായ വികാരങ്ങൾ ഒരു വാക്കിൽ ചേരുവ ചേർത്ത് കൊണ്ട് അമ്മ ചോദിച്ചു:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;'എന്താ?'&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അശനിപാതത്തിൽ ആകാശമേഘങ്ങളെ പോലെ അൺകിൾ ഗർജ്ജിച്ചു:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;'അവന്റെ താടിയും മുടിയും !!!'&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
സിംഹാസനത്തിൽ നിന്നും ഉയരാതെ ആൺട്ടി കൂട്ടിചേർത്തു:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;'ദേ മുഖത്തു ഒരു കുരുവും'&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഇത് കൂടി കേട്ടപ്പോൾ ഇഡലി തുണി പോലെ വിളറി നിന്നിരുന്ന പയ്യൻ പ്രസന്നവദനനായി. ശാന്തത ശ്വസിച്ചുകൊണ്ട്
പയ്യൻ എടുത്ത പത്രം താഴെ വച്ചു. എന്നിട്ട് ഇങ്ങനെ പറഞ്ഞു:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;'ഹാവൂ … എനിക്ക് സന്തോഷമായി. വാർത്തകളൊക്കെ അറിഞ്ഞ സ്ഥിതിക്ക് ഇനി പത്രം വായിക്കേണ്ടതില്ലലോ.'&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
മനസ്സിലായത് കൊണ്ട് അമ്മ അകത്തേക്കും, ആൺട്ടി അന്തർമുഖത്തിലേക്കും പോയി. മനസ്സിലാവാത്തത് കൊണ്ട് അൺകിൾ
ഹോർലിക്‌സ്-പാൽ അന്വേഷിച്ചു. അങ്ങനെയാണ് തന്റെ ഇരുപത്തിരണ്ട് വർഷത്തെ ശീലമായ പത്രവായന പയ്യൻ ഉപേക്ഷിച്ചത്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
വാർത്തകൾ വിശദമായി. സ്ഥലത്തെ പ്രധാന പയ്യൻ പത്രവായന നിർത്തി….
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>satire</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/pathra-vayana/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:15:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>City Rain</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/cityrain/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Like an ancient civilization, the city slept,&lt;br&gt;
In an endless commute, its way of life wept.&lt;br&gt;
In mirky buildings and sulky streets,&lt;br&gt;
Boredom grumbled, and happiness crumbled.&lt;br&gt;
Hither and yon, people ran to make ends meet,&lt;br&gt;
And that's when, the first drop of rain came to greet.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
His highness's arrival was announced by Dhol drums,&lt;br&gt;
Boisterously, it lifted the city out of its doldrums.&lt;br&gt;
Bewitched the wind, into a wicked poltergeist,&lt;br&gt;
Possessed the trees like an unseen ghost,&lt;br&gt;
Made them dance with no rhyme, nor reason,&lt;br&gt;
The city was under its spell, in a dry summer season.&lt;br&gt;
Windows were shattered; for wind owes nothing in the end.&lt;br&gt;
Clothes were brandished; so one shall never pretend.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, across the tar road, he boarded a bus, red,&lt;br&gt;
Sitting by a window, he peered outside - pandemonium appeared.&lt;br&gt;
Citizens with books, and bags, and sarees above their head,&lt;br&gt;
Steam rising, from a packed tea shop in the distance, up ahead,&lt;br&gt;
A woman was wrestling with wind; to ignite a cigarette,&lt;br&gt;
Strolling while nature is mopping; a singular etiquette.&lt;br&gt;
A buoyant umbrella was floating in a whirlwind,&lt;br&gt;
Nature, thus mocking the anticipation of humankind.&lt;br&gt;
The rain gained momentum as the bus coughed forward,&lt;br&gt;
He looked behind and saw memories travelleing backward.&lt;br&gt;
Closed his eyes, the downpour deluged his face with euphoria,&lt;br&gt;
A song surfaced from his childhood that rhymed with liquid nostalgia.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, she picked up the book, her precious company,&lt;br&gt;
The wooden arm chair, beckoned her from the spacious balcony;&lt;br&gt;
Feet up on the chair, rocking back and forth,&lt;br&gt;
She witnessed sky coalesce with earth.&lt;br&gt;
Closed her eyes; her breath flooded heart with petrichor,&lt;br&gt;
Opened the book; her brain vessels capsized in bibliochor.&lt;br&gt;
For once, her heart and brain agreed to this moment,&lt;br&gt;
That purpose of life is - Knowledge - makes one content.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, they said, let's keep playing,&lt;br&gt;
This can't get any better, keep the ball rolling.&lt;br&gt;
The rain couldn't drench their jerseys wet,&lt;br&gt;
For they were already saturated in sweat.&lt;br&gt;
Raindrops crossing flood lights was quite a sight,&lt;br&gt;
Win this special game, they must, with all their might.&lt;br&gt;
Awaits, a hot water bath, a biryani, and perhaps a drive into the night,&lt;br&gt;
When the city shines bright, and the night grows young until the first light.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, he sought her presence,&lt;br&gt;
She was not found in their residence.&lt;br&gt;
He looked at the flight of stairs,&lt;br&gt;
Spun on his feet, and went up to the terrace.&lt;br&gt;
There she stood staring at the sky,&lt;br&gt;
Palms open, her hands were lifted shoulder high.&lt;br&gt;
Her pink clothes soaked from head-to-toe,&lt;br&gt;
He moved closer and hugged her apropos.&lt;br&gt;
She stepped on his feet; He kissed on top of her head,&lt;br&gt;
With hands wrapped around his chest, her face rested.&lt;br&gt;
In that chilling juxtaposition, they stood in silence,&lt;br&gt;
Under the rain, they melded into the timeless ambience.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, Poet moved to the kitchen,&lt;br&gt;
For a cup of tea with a hint of mint and lemon.&lt;br&gt;
The curtains swung over the room irking the shadows,&lt;br&gt;
A venerable fountain pen lay on the table in its repose.&lt;br&gt;
The pen kissed the paper, then and back again,&lt;br&gt;
Until Poet read the words, "City Rain".&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/cityrain/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 15:59:20 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>