<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mindtoilet</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/</link><description>Mind Blogging</description><atom:link href="https://mindtoilet.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2025 &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com"&gt;mindtoilet&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 08:49:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>P.G. Wodehouse</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/wodehouse/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Dear Listener,
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The only way you can spoil a Wodehouse story is by not reading it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Welcome to Hitchens' Razor.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What is the irresistible charm of a Wodehouse story on a teenage boy living in a
remote village on a mountainous high range in tropical south Asia? What's Jeeves
and Blandings Castle books doing there? This episode is about the English
language maestro P.G. Wodehouse - a glimpse specifically for foreigners to
Britain.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
English has always been a confusing language for foreigners. Their struggle,
when studied along the semantics and phonetics of this enigmatic language
presents a satisfying conclusion that it is nothing but a mish-mash of received,
paradoxical words and phrases devotedly practised over multiple millennia. Its
vocabulary thus enriched with 'stuff' borrowed, stolen, or sometimes grabbed
from other places - just like the word 'grab', which has now seemingly been
inculcated into the cultural lexicon as an inappropriate but accepted verb
everywhere - most noticeable in coffee shops. Why would you grab a coffee? just
take it, especially if you have paid for it. Anyway, the victim languages, that
is to say most of the foreign languages, albeit complex, are often complete and
superior to English - what you speak is what you write is exactly what others
read in other languages. Have you ever wondered why English language cannot
handle a genre like Magic Realism? 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Yet, the language survived, it proliferated, and even ruled. I suppose a few
British and Irish people accepted its frailties and went beyond them; they
managed to put words in a certain order, which not just transformed the
sentences and the stories, but made the language itself irresistible to
outsiders. At the perch of that bunch of doyens is P.G. Wodehouse.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There are certain things that can be experienced, but not explained. To get a
novel right, an author needs to consummate four 'P's, says Stephen Fry: "Place,
People, Plot, and Prose". The place is more or less unchanging in Wodehousian
tales - all set in 18th century England or New York. The people he created,
perhaps, we could credit him lucky to have had the friends, family, surroundings
and upbringing for those imperishable characters. The plot, paraphrasing
Wodehouse's own words, "if you get the love story correct, then plot will
follow". But, the prose, that's what sets him apart. The way he puts one word
after another, separated by those impeccable punctuation, and the interweaving
of expanding humour realised without any profanity, but with clever
juxtaposition of words and ideas in those lines leaves a literary equivalent of
umami in reader's mind. Nobody knows how he managed that. I am safe of not
abusing the word 'genius' here.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I know what you are thinking listener: Well, that's all good, but there are
about a 100 books, where shall I begin? Whom should I acquaint with first? Is it
Bertie Wooster, Jeeves, Lord Emsworth, the Efficient Baxter, or PSmith with a
silent 'P', or all the overbearing aunties? Oh, please tell me where should I
begin?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Well, start at 'Something Fresh'.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It is the first book in Blandings Castle series. We are introduced to Blandings
Castle and Lord Emsworth, The Efficient Baxter, and a perfect love story.
Ehh… not between Emsworth and Baxter, but others in the story. Anyway, here
are few lines from the book 'Something Fresh', that might release you from
the furies of indecision. Here you go:
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
"The sunshine of a fair spring morning fell graciously upon London town. It was
the sort of morning when air gives us a feeling of anticipation, a feeling that,
on a day like this, things surely cannot go joggling along in a the same dull
groove, a premonition that something romantic and exciting is about to happen to
us."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"One does not fall in love with a girl whom one has met only three times. A
moment's reflection enabled him to diagnose his sensations correctly. The odd
impulse to leap across the compartment and kiss her was not love. It was merely
the natural desire of a good hearted young man to be decently chummy with his
species."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"They made poor old Percy look an absolute ass."
Well, Nature had done that already, but I'm bound to say they improved on
Nature's work. I should think your cousin Percy must have felt like a plucked
chicken."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Science with a thousand triumphs to her credit, has not yet succeeded in
discovering the correct reply for a young man to make who finds himself in the
appalling position of being apologised to by a pretty girl.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Ashe was becoming conscious of an undercurrent of something not altogether
agreeable in the conversation. It lacked the gay ease of their first
interview. He was not apprehensive lest she might have guessed his secret."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Trouble, after all, like beauty, is in the eye of the beholder."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Rupert Baxter, the Earl of Emsworth's indefatigable Private Secretary, was one
of those men whose chief characteristic is a vague suspicion of their fellow
human beings. He did not suspect them of this or that definite crime: he simply
suspected them."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Alright, that hopefully is the impetus you were craving. Remember, you can
only spoil a Wodehouse story by not reading it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Happy reading time!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Cheers.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/wodehouse/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 11:27:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>പയ്യന് ഗൃഹാതുരത്വം</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/payyanugruhathurathuam/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
പതിവിലും നേരത്തെ ഇന്ന് പയ്യൻ പബ്ബിൽ പോയി. എഡിൻബ്ര പഴയ പട്ടണത്തിലെ ഒരു പ്രാചീന ഗുഹയാണ്
താവളം. എത്തിനോക്കിയാൽ ഒരു ഭാഗത്ത് നോർത്ത് സീ കടലും, എത്തിനോക്കാതെതന്നെ മറുഭാഗത്ത് ആർതർ സീറ്റ്
കുന്നും കാണാം. വാതിൽ തള്ളിനീക്കിയപ്പോൾ ശബ്ദകലപില. പയ്യനെ കണ്ടതും ബാറിനടുത്തുനിന്നും സാം ചോദിച്ചു:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ഓൾറൈറ്റ്  പയ്യൻ? നിന്റെ ഐഡി ഒന്ന് കാണണം."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കുറേ വർഷങ്ങൾക്ക് മുൻപ് ആദ്യമായി അവിടെ ചെന്നപ്പോൾ സാം ഇതേ ചോദ്യം ചോദിച്ച് പറ്റിച്ചതാണ്. അന്ന് ഐഡി
പരതിയപ്പോൾ എല്ലാവരും കൂടി ചിരിച്ചു. സാം അവിടത്തെ സ്ഥിരകാരനാണ്, അധികാരിയല്ല. ഇന്ന് ചെറുതായി ഒന്ന്
ചിരിച്ചുകൊണ്ട് സാമിനുള്ള സ്ഥിരം മറുപടി കൊടുത്തു:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"സ്റ്റിൽ ലൂക്കിങ് ഫോർ ഇറ്റ് സാം"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കൊമ്പുകോർത്ത് നിൽക്കുന്ന ബിയർ ടാപ്പുകളുടെയടുത്ത് ചെന്നപ്പോൾ പേർമ് ജോൺ, ബാർമൻ, പയ്യനെ നോക്കി
ചിരിച്ചു. നെറുകിൽ നിന്നും നെറ്റിയിലേക്ക് മുടി ചുരുട്ടി നിലകൊള്ളിക്കുന്ന ആധുനികമെന്നഭിപ്രായപെടുന്ന
കേശഫാഷനാണ് 'പേർമ്'.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"പൈന്റ് ഓഫ് ലാഗാ, പയ്യൻ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ജോൺ, മേറ്റ്, എനിക്കിന്ന് അതിരുകവിഞ്ഞ നൊസ്റ്റാൾജിയ; ഉപ്പും പഞ്ചസാരയുമിട്ട ഒരു ഗ്ലാസ്
നാരങ്ങവെള്ളം തരൂ."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ജോൺ മുഖം തിരിച്ച് മറ്റുള്ളവരെ നോക്കി.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എവിടെ നിന്നോ പ്രൊഫസർ ലാറ പയ്യന്റെ അടുത്തേക്ക് വന്നു. കണ്ണട നാസികസേതുവിൽ നിന്നും സാധാരണമായി
നേത്രസേതുവിലേക്ക് നീക്കികൊണ്ട് അവർ ചോദിച്ചു:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"യു ഓക്കെ ഡാർലിംഗ്"?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ലാറ, ലൗ, എന്റെ ഓർമ്മകളിൽ ചിതലരിക്കുന്നു"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"അതൊരു ചിതലരിക്കുന്ന പ്രയോഗമല്ലേ പയ്യൻ"?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ലാറ, എന്തുകൊണ്ടോ ബിലജമുനി വാൽമീകിയെ സ്മരിച്ചുപോകുന്നു ഈ നിമിഷം. ഒരു ചിതൽപുറ്റിന്റെയുള്ളിൽ
ജീവിക്കാൻ ബുദ്ധിമുട്ടായിരിക്കുമല്ലേ?  മങ്ങിയകാഴ്ചകൾ. ഞാൻ ഏറ്റവും കൂടുതൽ സ്നേഹിക്കുന്ന എന്റെ
ബാല്യകാലം ഇന്ന് ഇളനീർകുഴമ്പ് ഒറ്റിച്ച കണ്ണുകളിലൂടെയാണ് ഞാൻ അറിയുന്നത്. കുട്ടിക്കാലത്തിന്റെ പഞ്ചവർണ്ണകവാടം
എന്റെ മുന്നിൽ കൊട്ടിയടയ്ക്കപ്പെടുകയാണോ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"നീ ഭൂതകാലത്തെ ഇത്ര മാത്രം സ്നേഹിക്കുന്നുവല്ലോ പയ്യൻ."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ഓർമ്മകളുണ്ടെങ്കിൽ പിന്നെ നഷ്ടങ്ങളില്ലലോ ലാറ."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ലാറ ഒന്നും പറയാതെ എന്തോ പെട്ടെന്നോർത്തപോലെ ഇമചിമ്മാതെയിരുന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
പേർമ് ജോൺ നാരങ്ങവെള്ളം കൊണ്ടുവന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
വെള്ളം കുടിച്ചപ്പോൾ പാലക്കാടൻ ഉൾഗ്രാമത്തിൽ ഒരു കുളത്തിന്റെ വക്കത്ത് മഴത്തുള്ളികൾ വെള്ളത്തിലേക്ക്
വീഴുന്നത് നോക്കി ചൂണ്ടയിട്ടിരികുന്ന ട്രൗസറിട്ട ഒരു കുട്ടിയുടെ ചിത്രം മനസ്സിലേക്ക് വന്നു. എത്രയോർത്തിട്ടും
ട്രൗസറിന്റെ നിറം തെളിയുന്നില്ല!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
പയ്യന്റെ കണ്ണിൽ നിന്നും മഴപെയ്യാൻ തുടങ്ങി. ഇതുകണ്ട പേർമ് ജോൺ ഒരു സിംഗിൾ മാൾട്ട് വിസ്കി സിംഗിൾ
പയ്യന്റെ മുന്നിൽ വച്ചു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ഓൺ ദി ഹൗസ്, പയ്യൻ"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
സ്ഥിരക്കാർ ചുറ്റും കൂടി.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ചിയേർസ് പയ്യൻ! ഓർമ്മകളുടെ ഓർമ്മയ്ക്കായി"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ചിയേർസ്". പയ്യൻ മൂക്ക് ഗ്ലാസിന്റെയുള്ളിൽ ഒന്ന് ചുഴറ്റി പ്രദിക്ഷണം വച്ച ശേഷം ഗ്ലാസ് ഒന്ന് മേശയിൽ മുട്ടിച്ച് ഒരു സിപ്പ് കുടിച്ചു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"കേ നാ പോയ, നാ ഫോയ. ഇഫ് യു ഡോണട്ട് ടാപ്പ്, യു ഡോണട്ട് …."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എല്ലാവരും ചിരിച്ചു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ചുറ്റും കൂടിയവരിൽ നിന്നും ആരോ പറഞ്ഞു:
"എപ്പോഴത്തെയും പോലെ ഒരു തമാശ പറയു പയ്യൻ. പുതിയത്."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഹാസ്യത്തിനുള്ള അവസ്ഥയില്ല എന്ന് ദയയ്ക്കുവേണ്ടി പാരവശ്യം കേണു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"പറ പയ്യൻ, തമാശ പറ പയ്യൻ" 
 പിന്നിൽ നിന്നാരോ ഇക്കിളിപെടുത്തി. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ശരി ശരി. ജൂതന്മാരുടെ ഉള്ളിയുടെ പേരെന്താണ് ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
നിശ്ശബ്‌ദത.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"അറിയില്ല", "ങ്ഹും", "ങ്ഹേ" 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ഷലോട്ട്", പയ്യൻ പറഞ്ഞു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 നിശ്ശബ്‌ദത, പിന്നെ പൊട്ടിച്ചിരി. വീണ്ടും ചീയർസ്. ആ ലഹരിയിൽ എല്ലാവരും പിരിഞ്ഞു പോയി. തോളിൽ തട്ടി ആരോ പറഞ്ഞു:
"ഹീ ഈസ് ബാക്ക്"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ലാറ മാത്രം അവിടെ തന്നെ ഇരുന്നു. പയ്യന്റെ സമനിലയെ ശുശ്രുഷിക്കാൻ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ഫലിതം കൊള്ളാമായിരുന്നു പയ്യൻ"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"നന്ദി ലാറ. നിന്റെ കുട്ടികൾക്ക് പറഞ്ഞു കൊടുക്കു. ഒരു പിടി ഓർമ്മകൾ, രണ്ടു കുട്ടികൾ"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"അതാണല്ലേ ജീവിതം?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"അതല്ലേ, ലാറ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"എനിക്കും തോന്നുന്നു. എന്താണ് നീ ഇന്നിത്ര വിഷമിക്കാൻ കാരണം?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"നഷ്ടപെടുന്ന ബാല്യകാലസ്മരണകൾ, അതിന്റെ തിരിച്ചറിവ്"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"നിന്റെ ബാല്യം നിനക്കത്ര വിലപ്പെട്ടതാണോ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"പേടി തോന്നുന്നു. ചിത്രങ്ങളിലും, വാക്കുകളിലും ഇല്ലാത്ത എത്രയോ നിമിഷങ്ങൾ. എന്റേതാണെന്ന്
അവകാശപ്പെടാൻ അർഹതയുള്ള ഓർമ്മകൾ, അതില്ലാതാവുന്നു"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"മറവി വരമല്ലേ പയ്യൻ, ശാപമല്ലല്ലോ"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ദ്വൈതമു സുഖമാ, അദ്വൈതമു സുഖമാ എന്ന ധാരയായല്ലോ ലാറ"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"നിനക്ക് പ്രായമേറിയെന്ന്  തോന്നുന്നുണ്ടോ പയ്യൻ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ഉണ്ടല്ലോ. ചില സിനിമകളൊന്നും കാണാൻ പറ്റുന്നില്ല. അവലംബിക്കാൻ ധൈര്യമില്ല. കരയിപ്പിക്കുമോ എന്നൊരു
ഭയം. കഥാസാരം മുൻ‌കൂർ വായിച്ചറിയാൻ ഒരാവേശം. ആരൊക്കെയോ എവിടെ നിന്നൊക്കെയോ തിരിഞ്ഞു നോക്കുന്നത്
പോലെ"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"അത് പ്രായത്തിന്റേതെന്ന് നീ വിശ്വസിക്കുന്നുവോ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ഉവ്വ്. ഇരുപതുകളുടെ തുടക്കത്തിൽ ആവേശത്തിരി കൊളുത്തിയത് സിനിമകളും നോവലുകളുമാണ്. അനീതി തന്നെ അന്നും
ശത്രു. അതിനെ ചെറുക്കാനും, ഇല്ലാതാക്കാനും വേണ്ടി പോരാടാൻ തോന്നിയിരുന്നു. സാമൂഹികസേവനത്തിനുവേണ്ടി
ജീവിക്കാനും. പ്രധാനമന്ത്രിയാവാൻ വരെ തയ്യാറായിരുന്നു. പിന്നെ പിന്നെ ആരൊക്കെയോ ഉപദേശിക്കാൻ
തുടങ്ങി. പ്രാരാബ്‌ധങ്ങൾക്കുവേണ്ടിയായി പോരാട്ടം, ജോലിക്ക് വേണ്ടിയായി ജീവിതം. സമ്പാദിക്കും തോറും
പ്രാരാബ്‌ധങ്ങളേറി. സ്വയം സഹായിക്കാനേ കഴിഞ്ഞുള്ളു. സന്തോഷിപ്പിക്കുന്ന സിനിമകൾ മാത്രം കാണാൻ
ആഗ്രഹിച്ചു. ചിന്തിപ്പിക്കുന്ന നോവെലുകൾ ഒഴിവാക്കി. ഹിപ്പോക്രസി എന്ന ജുഗുപ്സാവഹമായ വാക്കിന്റെ അർത്ഥം
ഇതിനിടെക്കെന്നോ സ്വാംശീകരിച്ചു. നിരാലംബനായി തുടർന്നു. നിസ്സഹായതയിൽ നിന്നും
നിസ്സംഗതയുണ്ടായി. നിസ്സംഗതയിൽ നിന്നും കൂടുതൽ നിസ്സഹായതയങ്കുരിച്ചു. വിനയം മാത്രം ബാക്കി."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"സിനിമ നിന്റെ ഗേറ്റ്വേയും ഗെറ്റവേയും ആയിരുന്നില്ലേ പയ്യൻ. അതും നിന്നെ പറ്റിച്ചോ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ഞാൻ പറഞ്ഞില്ലേ ആരൊക്കയോ തിരിഞ്ഞു നോക്കുന്നു എന്ന്. ബന്ധങ്ങൾ, വേണ്ടപ്പെട്ടവർ, മിത്രങ്ങൾ അവരാണ്
ഇടകണ്ണിടുന്നതും ചെവിയിലോതുന്നതും. എന്നിലവരും അവരിലിൽ ഞാനും ഭാഗികമായി
ജീവിക്കുന്നു. കല്ലിൻമേൽപ്പലക, കണ്ണടച്ചാൽ അനന്തമായ കല്ലോലങ്ങൾ, ഒരു വക്കിൽ നിന്നാടുകയാണ്. കണ്ണ്
തുറന്നാലറിയുന്നു കസേരപലകയിൽത്തന്നെയാണ് പിടിച്ചിരിയ്ക്കുന്നത് എന്ന്. എന്നാലും
കണ്ഠത്തിലതേയുത്ക്കണ്ഠ. വീണ്ടും കണ്ണടക്കുമ്പോൾ കാണുന്നത് ഒരു നേർത്ത ചരടാണ്. ഒരറ്റം കാണാൻകഴിയാത്ത
തന്തു. ആരൊക്കയോ അതിൽ തൂങ്ങുന്നു, ചിലർ നിന്നാടുന്നു, കൂടാതെ എന്തൊക്കെയോ അതിൽ കെട്ടിയിരിക്കുന്നു. ആ
ചരടിൽ എന്റെ ലോകം മുഴുവനുമുണ്ടെന്ന് തോന്നി. ചരടിന്റെ മറ്റേ അറ്റം എന്റെ കൈയിൽ!  എന്തിനാ എന്റെ
കൈയിൽ തന്നേ? എങ്ങാനും പൊട്ടിയാലോ? വെള്ളത്തിൽ മുക്കിയ അപ്പൂപ്പൻതാടി പോലെയായല്ലോ ഞാൻ."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"എന്തൊക്കെയാ പയ്യൻ നീ പറയുന്നത് ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ചിരിപ്പിക്കുന്ന സിനിമകൾ മാത്രമെടുത്താൽ പോരെ ലാറ. പുതിയകാര്യങ്ങൾ എന്നെ അറിയിക്കാൻ നോക്കുമ്പോൾ
പഴയ കാര്യങ്ങൾ തന്നെയാണ് ഞാൻ കൂടുതൽ അറിയുന്നത്."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"പറയൂ പയ്യൻ, ഞാൻ വീണ്ടും ചോദിക്കട്ടെ, മറവി വരമോ ശാപമോ ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"ടൂഷേ ലാറ, ടൂഷേ."
"വരം, ശാപം, ഒന്ന് മറ്റൊന്നിന് വളമായി തീരുന്നു. ഓർക്കാനാഗ്രഹിക്കുന്നത് മറന്ന്
പോകുന്നു. ഗൃഹാതുരത്വം എൽ. പി. സ്കൂൾ ടീച്ചറെ പോലെ ചൂരലുപയോഗിക്കുന്നു. കുട്ടിക്കാലത്ത് ഒരു ദിവസം ഉച്ചയ്ക്ക്
ഞാൻ കുളത്തിന്റെ വക്കത്തിരിക്കുകയായിരുന്നു. ചൂണ്ടയിട്ടിട്ടുണ്ട്. പെട്ടെന്ന് വെളിച്ചം കുറഞ്ഞു. ആകാശത്തിൽ
നിന്നും ഒരു ഗർജ്ജനം. കാർമേഘങ്ങൾ റോൾകോളിന് വന്നു നിരന്ന് നിന്നു. ഞാൻ ചൂണ്ട വലിച്ച് മേലോട്ട് നോക്കി
ചിരിച്ചു. മഴയെ എന്നും സ്നേഹിച്ചിട്ടേയുള്ളു. ആദ്യത്തെ തുള്ളി ഒരാവേശമാണ്. അത് കണ്ണിൽ തന്നെ
വീണു. പതിക്കുന്നതിന് തൊട്ടുമുൻപ് ഞാൻ പീലികളടച്ചു. കൈ നീട്ടി ചിരിച്ചു. നല്ല മഴ. കുളത്തിലേക്ക് എടുത്ത്
ചാടി. മലർന്ന് നീന്തി മുഖത്ത് മഴ വാങ്ങി. അടുത്തൊന്നും ആരുമില്ല. ആ വലിയ കുളത്തിൽ ഞാനും ജലജീവികളും
മാത്രം. മരങ്ങൾ ചുറ്റും പലഭാഗത്ത് നിന്നും എത്തി നോക്കുന്നു. അതിൽ കിളികളുണ്ടാവണം. കാറ്റടിക്കുന്നുണ്ട്. മഴ
ശക്തമാവുന്നു. മലർന്നും കമിഴ്ന്നും ഞാനെന്റെ ജലക്രീഡ തുടർന്നു. അങ്ങനെ എത്ര നേരം. പക്ഷെ ഇട്ടിരുന്ന
ട്രൗസറിന്റെ നിറം ഓർമ്മയില്ല. ഓർത്തിരുന്നതാണ്. ഒരിക്കലും മറക്കില്ലെന്ന് കരുതിയതും. ഇനി ഞാൻ ചൂണ്ട
മറക്കും, എത്തിനോക്കുന്ന മരങ്ങളെയും അതിലെ പക്ഷികളെയും മറക്കും, കുളം മറക്കും, മഴ മറക്കും, എന്നെ തന്നെ
മറക്കും, അല്ലേ ലാറ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ലാറയുടെ കണ്ണുകളിൽ മഴ പെയ്യുന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"അതെ പയ്യൻ, നീ എല്ലാം മറക്കും, ഞാനും മറക്കും, എല്ലാവരും മറക്കും. പക്ഷേ, ഒന്ന് മാത്രം മറക്കില്ല."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"എന്താത്?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"നീന്താൻ നീ ഒരിക്കലും മറക്കില്ല, നീയും, ഞാനും, എല്ലാവരും നീന്തികൊണ്ടേയിരിക്കും."
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>പയ്യൻ</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/payyanugruhathurathuam/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 18:25:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chemeen - book review</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/chemeen-review/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Thakazhi has awarded a free pass into the theme park of his characters' minds;
to embark on its topsy-turvy rides one at a time. An allowance is issued to
trespass deep into their emotions without prosecution, to stay abreast with
their feelings of existence, ambition, conformity, judgement, justification, and
finally, acceptance. You are cajoled into forgetting self and the author. At no
point is one invited to project their own sensory experiences of joy and plight
to that of any character, nor is asked to care about author's circumstances or
intentions. Death of the author, and oddly enough, also of the reader, is
registered. One subconsciously melds into a seaside belonging to Karuthamma, the
protagonist, Chakki, her mother, Chembankunju, her father, Pareekutty, her
lover, Palani, her husband, and their individual soliloquies.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is no question of right and wrong, everyone is so, and so perhaps everyone
is wrong. One would certainly be defiant in attempting to distance from that
premise, for it might upset our convenience to earmark a villain at the outset.
There isn't a conspicuous one in this story. In essence, love is punished, by
forces invisible - of collective unconscious, orthodoxy, taboo, customs, fear,
righteousness, ambition, gossips, jealousy, helplessness, debt, law of the land,
and ultimately the person inside you.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Karuthamma and Pareekutty grew up as childhood mates in a coastal village
unbeknownst to each other that they were to be separated when they get older.
Their love was that of the permanent nest made in each other's mind, and of the
words exchanged and laughter shared. In their life they never touch each other.
Yet he was ruined and she was blamed for existence. Why were they deemed guilty?
Were they deserving of such a verdict? Of course they were guilty of living rent
free in each other's heads, which also belonged to their family and the
community. There is a tax to be paid on thoughts, especially if one is thinking
of love. Even more important was the hubris, their negligence: towards the
supernatural, to their belief in traditions and the omnipresent deity of
uncertainties, the &lt;i&gt;'Kadalamma'&lt;/i&gt;, the mother of the ocean. Everyone in that
community has had given a tacit consent at birth to be owned by the ocean and
the community they were born into, to its customs and rules. Being unamenable to
those benchmarks forges one into an accused, self-accused, implicit criminal of
invisible thought crimes, of which one cannot be absolved. Such a deed makes one
a bounty, a prey, a victim!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One is informed about the ambitious and avaricious father, the astute and
confused mother, and the strong helpless husband. The tragedy manifests in the
realisation that one cannot escape the bond of blood, as much as there is no
escape from the bond of &lt;i&gt;'anuragam'&lt;/i&gt; (love); eternally bound by those, in the
most cruel, sadomasochist manner, where you constantly reinforce your own
conviction of being at fault, your life a burden to others, your love
disrupts peace. Once committed, knowingly or otherwise, there is no redemption,
because it transforms you into your own torturer, to become your own judge,
jury and executioner.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But eventually all that will disappear from memory for a timeless melody and an
everlasting embrace. By its own inimitable, inexplicable ways, love always
triumphs! When Pareekutty sings his heart out, Kaurthamma will always walk
towards him with the unadulterated clarity and perfect equanimity of mind. That
attraction, like everything else, is also beyond her control, perhaps aligning
with the laws of nature, subduing the ensuing repercussions, whatever the price
may be for that tryst, even if permanent solitude, love triumphs!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>review</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/chemeen-review/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>പയ്യന്റെ സാധനം കാണാനില്ല</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/saadhanamkannanilla/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
അസതോമ സദ് ഗമയാ എന്നാണ് ആദ്യ വരി വായിച്ചപ്പോൾ ൻറ്റെ മനസ്സിൽ തോന്നിയത്. ഒരീസം രാവിലെ ഗ്രിഗർ സാംസ
സ്വന്തം കിടക്കയിൽ ഒരു കൂറാനായി രൂപാന്തരപ്രാപ്തികൊണ്ടു. രാത്രി ചാച്ചാൻ പോയപ്പോൾ കുഴപ്പമൊന്നും
ഉണ്ടായിരുന്നില്ലത്രേ. കാഫ്കയെ സൂക്ഷിക്കണം എന്ന് മനസ്സിൽ കുറിച്ചാണ് പുസ്തകം കമിഴ്ത്തി ഉറങ്ങാൻ കിടന്നത്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
രാവിലെയായീന്ന് മുട്ടിയപ്പോൾ മനസ്സിലായി. ആദ്യം മൂക്കൊന്ന് ചൊറിഞ്ഞു. പിന്നെ പുതപ്പിന്റെ മേലെ
കാളിയമർദ്ദനം. സ്വിച്ചിട്ട് വെളിച്ചത്തിനെ തുറന്ന് വിട്ടു. കൂസലൊന്നുമില്ലാതെ കൂസിലേക്ക് നടന്നു. സീറ്റ്
ഉയർത്തി, തുണി താഴ്ത്തി. ങ്ഹേ!&lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
കാണാനില്ല, സാധനം കാണാനില്ല!&lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
തപ്പി നോക്കി, തടവി നോക്കി. ഇല്ല, സത്യം. ഒന്ന് പാദഹസ്താസനം ചെയ്തു - ഉറപ്പിച്ചുന്നങ്ങട് ഉറപ്പു
വരുത്താൻ. കണ്ടില്ല. പതറി, ശെരിക്കും പതറി. ഒരു പത്തരമാറ്റ് പതറൽ. പാലപ്പൂവിന്റെ ഗന്ധവുമായി ഒരു
പാലക്കാടൻ കാറ്റ് എവിടെനിന്നോ ഒരു ഉപമയുമായി പറന്നെത്തി. ആ ശിഥില നിമിഷത്തിൽ ജീവിതത്തിന്റെ
സുഖദുഃഖങ്ങളുടെ ജക്സ്റ്റപൊസിഷൻ എന്താണെന്നാലോചിച്ചു. കിട്ടിയില്ല. ഇതുവരെയുള്ള ജീവിതത്തിന്റെ
കർമ്മബന്ധങ്ങളെല്ലാം പെട്ടെന്നറ്റുപോയതുപോലെ തോന്നി.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കൈ തലയിൽ വച്ചതെപ്പോഴാണെന്നോർമ്മയില്ല. അങ്ങനെ തന്നെ തിരിഞ്ഞു മുറിയില്ലേക്ക് നടന്നു. ചവിട്ടികൂട്ടിയ
പുതപ്പാണ് ആദ്യം വലിച്ചുനോക്കിയത്. കോസറി മുഴുവൻ തലോടി, തപ്പി നോക്കി, തടവി നോക്കി. ങ്ഹേ
ഹേ. തലേണയുടെയടിയിൽ നോക്കി. ശൂന്യം. കസേരയിലില്ല. കുളിമുറിയിൽ ഒന്ന് നോക്കി, ഇല്ല. തിരുമ്പാനുള്ള
തുണികൾ ഇട്ടിരിക്കുന്ന വട്ടി കണ്ടു. ചിന്തകളിൽ ഒരു വെള്ളിവര. കീടത്തെ ചികയുന്ന പെട കോഴിയെ പോലെ
വസ്ത്രങ്ങളോരോന്നായി എറിഞ്ഞു. കൗപീനങ്ങളോരോന്നും കുടഞ്ഞു. എങ്ങുമില്ല. വട്ടി
കമിഴ്ത്തി. ശൂന്യാദിശൂന്യം. ഇനി എന്ത്? ശരീരഭാരം കുറഞ്ഞപ്പോൾ ദുഃഖഭാരം കൂടുന്നു. ആകെ ഒരു
ഇരുട്ട്. തമസോമാ ജ്യോതിർ ഗമയ, പ്ളീസ്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഒന്ന് കണ്ണടച്ച് ശ്വാസം വലിച്ചു. ഒരു നിഴലാട്ടം പോലെ അവളുടെ മുഖം. ഉടനെ അവളെ വിളിച്ചു, വീണ്ടും
വിളിച്ചു, വീണ്ടും, വീണ്ടും വിളിച്ചു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"&lt;i&gt;ഹലോ.&lt;/i&gt;"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അസഭ്യാദികൾ അവൾ വർഷിക്കുന്നതിന്മുൻപേ ഞാൻ സംഗതി രണ്ടര ശ്വാസത്തിൽ പറഞ്ഞുമുഴുമിച്ചു. പക്ഷേ, രണ്ട്
ആംഗലേയവാക്കുകളിൽ അവൾ ഇംഗിതം അറിയിച്ചു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഞാൻ വീണ്ടും വിളിച്ചു. വീണ്ടും, വീണ്ടും വിളിച്ചു. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"&lt;i&gt;നിന്റെ സമയം അടുത്തിരിക്കുന്നു പയ്യൻ.&lt;/i&gt;"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"അരുതേ! ബന്ധം നീ മുറിക്കരുതേ! സുകൃതിനി, കൃശഗാത്രി, കമലനയനെ, നിന്റെ കരിമ്പടം ഒന്ന്
കുടഞ്ഞുനോക്കു. അല്ലെങ്കിൽ വേണ്ട, അലക്ക് വട്ടിയിൽ ഒന്ന് കണ്ണോടിക്കൂ. സാധ്യതയുണ്ടുണ്ടാവാൻ. നഷ്ടപ്പത്തിന്റെ
വില നിന്നോട് ഞാൻ അതിശയോക്തിചേർത്തിപറയേണ്ട കാര്യമില്ലല്ലോ."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കൃശഗാത്രി എന്നുവിളിച്ചത്തിൽ അവളുടെ കവിളുകൾ ചുവന്ന് തുടുത്തിട്ടുണ്ടാവണം. കുറച്ച് നിശബ്ദത അവളെനിക്ക്
സമ്മാനിച്ചു. അവളുടെ ചെറുചലനങ്ങൾ മാത്രം അപ്പുറത്ത്. ശേഷം ഒരു വാക്ക്. ബന്ധം വീണ്ടും മുറിഞ്ഞു.
ഇന്നിവിടെ പയ്യൻ തോൽക്കുകയാണ്.&lt;br&gt;
ഒന്നിരുന്നു. ഇനി എന്ത്? എന്തെന്ത്? മൃത്യോമ അമൃതം ഗമയക്കുള്ള സമയമായോ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അവളെന്റെ, അല്ലെങ്കിൽ വേണ്ട, ഇവളെന്റെ ഓർമകളിൽ താമസമാക്കിട്ടിപ്പെത്ര കാലായി? ഒരു കത്തിലൂടെ
അനാവരണം ചെയ്യപ്പെട്ടതാണീബന്ധം. കളിയാക്കലാണ് അവളുടെ ശ്രുതി. ചെറുപ്പത്തിൽ തന്നെ കുറെ
വായിച്ചുകൂട്ടിട്ടിണ്ട്. ആ കാര്യത്തിലൊരസൂയ ബാക്കി നിൽക്കുന്നു. പണ്ട് മുഖ്യമന്ത്രിക്ക് ഇവൾ ഊമകത്തയച്ചിരുന്നു. കത്തിൽ
ഒന്നും പറഞ്ഞില്ല. കുറച്ച് ആംഗ്യങ്ങൾ മാത്രം. രാവിലെ ഓടാൻ പോയിരുന്നു പയ്യൻ. ചീറിപായ്യുന്ന എസ്കോർട്ട്
വാഹനകൾക്ക് നടുവിൽ നിന്ന് ഒരു വെള്ള കാറിന്റെ ജനലിലൂടെ ചുരുട്ടികൂട്ടിയ ഒരു കടലാസ്സ് പയ്യന്റെ മുഖത്ത് വന്ന്
വീണു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"കള്ള ഞാഞ്ഞൂലിന്റെ മോനെ, അട്ടയ്ക്കുണ്ടായവനെ", പയ്യൻ ഗർജ്ജിച്ചു.  "സ്വന്തം നാട് മലിനമാക്കുന്നോടാ?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ആരും കേട്ടില്ല. കടലാസ്സ് തുറന്ന് നോക്കി. ആദ്യം പിടികിട്ടിയില്ല. രണ്ടാമത് നോക്കിയപ്പോൾ രണ്ട് നന്ദി,
ഒരു മിത-അശലീല ആംഗ്യ ഫലിത പിജി-12 കവിത, ഒരു മുന്നറിയിപ്പ്, പിന്നെ ഒരു കടങ്കഥ. അന്നുതന്നെ
കടങ്കഥയുടെ ഉത്തരം പത്രത്തിൽ പരസ്യമായി കൊടുത്തു. മറുപടി,'&lt;i&gt;പ്രേമിക്കാനാഗ്രഹിക്കുന്നു&lt;/i&gt;' എന്ന തലകെട്ടിൽ
അതേ ആഴ്ച്ച പത്രത്തിൽ പരസ്യം വന്നു, കൂടെ ഒരു പുതിയ കടങ്കഥയും. അതിന്റെ ഉത്തരം അവളുടെ നമ്പർ
ആയിരുന്നു. അന്ന് തന്നെ ആ നമ്പറിൽ വിളിച്ചു. സംഗതി ഞാൻ രണ്ടര ശ്വാസത്തിൽ പറഞ്ഞു. അവൾ നിശബ്ദത
സമ്മാനിച്ചു. തുടർന്ന് ഞാൻ ചോദിച്ച ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഒറ്റവാക്കിൽ മറുപടി. 'ഉവ്വ്'
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ആ ഓർമ്മ പക്ഷെ ഈ അവസ്ഥയിൽ സുഖകരമായി തോന്നിയില്ല. ഒരേ ഇരുപ്പ് തന്നെ. വിരഹം, സങ്കർഷം, എല്ലാം
തത്സമയം. വിഷമിക്കാൻ അസംഖ്യം കാരണങ്ങൾ ഇതിനുമുൻപ് ലഭിച്ചിട്ടുണ്ട്, പക്ഷെ ഇത്…കഠിനം. വെള്ളിവര
തേടി മനസ്സ് വീണ്ടും വ്യാകുലപെട്ടു. ഇന്നത്തെ അവളുടെ മറുപടി '&lt;i&gt;ഇല്ല&lt;/i&gt;' എന്നായിരുന്നു. അവളെ ഓർത്തപ്പോൾ
മുത്തശ്ശി മനസ്സിലേക്ക് വന്നു. രണ്ട് പേർക്കും ഒരേ സ്വഭാവമാണ്. ഈ സമയത്ത് ഓർക്കാതിരിക്കുന്നതെങ്ങനെയാണ്?
മുത്തശ്ശിയല്ലേ… പെട്ടെന്ന് മുത്തശ്ശിയുടെ സ്ഥിരം വാചകം ഓർമ്മ വന്നു. കുന്തം പോയാൽ കുടത്തിലും
തപ്പണം. ചാടി എണീറ്റു. കിട്ടി. കട്ടിലൊന്ന് നീക്കി എത്തിനോക്കി. അതാ അവിടെ കിടന്ന്
തിളങ്ങുന്നു. പരന്ന് കിടന്ന് നീണ്ടുവലിഞ്ഞു കയ്യിട്ടെടുത്തു. കുട്ടിക്കാലം മുതൽ കൂടെയുണ്ടായിരുന്ന
വെള്ളിയരഞ്ഞാണം! ആദ്യവട്ടം സ്കൂളിൽ നിന്ന് സസ്‌പെൻഡ് ആയതിന് മുത്തശ്ശി സമ്മാനിച്ചതാണീയരഞ്ഞാണം. അതിന്റെ
കുടുക്ക് പൊട്ടിയിരിക്കുന്നു. ഇന്ന് തന്നെ മാറ്റണം. ഒന്നും നാളത്തേക്ക് മാറ്റരുത് എന്നാണല്ലോ. എന്തായാലും സാധനം
കിട്ടിയല്ലോ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഓം ശാന്തി ശാന്തി ശാന്തി ഹി.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>comedy</category><category>satire</category><category>പയ്യൻ</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/saadhanamkannanilla/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:16:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Political Ideologies - Edmund Burke vs Thomas Paine</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/pi_four/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Welcome to Hitchens' Razor.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Let's jump straight into it. I will thank our sources in the end.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Simply put, "Liberalism was the ideology of the rising middle class,
Conservatism was the ideology of the aristocracy or nobility, and Socialism was
the ideology of the growing working class." writes Andrew Heywood.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In other words, the origins of these three ideologies were associated with the
plight of the working class, aristocracy, and middle class; in different ways.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Let's begin with an anecdote about the origin of the terms 'left', and 'right'.
Do you remember the rendezvous of the Estates-General at the start of French
Revolution? When they gathered, the representatives who sought fundamental
changes to the functioning of the country sat on the left side of the presiding
officer, and the representatives who wanted to preserve the status quo sat on
the right side. In simple terms - on the left were those who wanted change, and
on right were those who resisted it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The following centuries after the revolution saw this left-right divide
traversing far and wide in space; and it still continues to divide the room. An
ideological watermark has been ever since impressed on all macro global events
and micro coffee shop chats. What changed was the shape of the
spectrum. Originally started as a straight line this eventually been bent by
extreme ideas and actions. It is now best visualised as a horse-shoe spectrum of
ideologies.  The extreme right and extreme left ideologies are reflected on a
convex mirror where their motives and actions seem closer than they appear. They
are hence within a within a kissing distance, and is dangerous.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So, how do we begin to fathom this theory?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps with the earliest political and ideological duel between Edmund Burke
and Thomas Paine!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orga02dbdf" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orga02dbdf"&gt;Burke vs Paine - The beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orga02dbdf"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Burke was born in 1729 CE, and Paine was born in 1737 CE. Burke was Irish, Paine
was English. They both supported the American Revolution; that is to say opposed
the English parliament and its monarch on the matter. If you remember our early
episodes in this series, one of the root causes for the American revolution was
Britain demanding more money from its American colonies to make up for the
losses incurred in its involvement in the Seven Years war. Burke and Paine was
against this new taxation on the colonies. Well, then they were friends!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The French also supported the American revolution, you see. They had lost dearly
in the Seven Years war, and sought revenge against their arch rivals, the
British. The bitter resentment was carried on until they helped the American
colonies defeat the British in the revolution. But the moral victory defeated
them materially. The war drove the French Kingdom to bankruptcy. One of the root
causes for the French revolution was the Monarch and his &lt;i&gt;ancien regime&lt;/i&gt; trying
to recover the losses by taxing its populace further.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Thomas Paine fully supported the French Revolution. In fact, he was an advisor
to the French National Assembly when they were drafting the new Constitution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Edmund Burke did not know how to react initially to the revolution. In August
1789, Burke wrote:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"England gazing with astonishment at a French struggle for liberty and not
knowing whether to blame or applaud! The thing indeed, thought I thought I saw
something like it in progress for several years, has still something in it
paradoxical and mysterious. The spirit it is impossible not to admire; but the
old Parisian ferocity has broken out in a shocking manner"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But, in October 1789, when a crowd of Parisian women marched on Versailles to
compel King Louis XVI to return to Paris, Burke lost it. That event took him to
his boiling point. Burke began to abhor the revolution. So he voiced and printed
words against the revolution and its principles, to which Paine replied
vehemently. And they became bitter rivals.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org77c9a24" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org77c9a24"&gt;Burke&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org77c9a24"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Edmund Burke is considered as the founder or father of conservatism, especially
in Britain. In 1790, he registered his reaction to the revolution in France by
publishing a pamphlet titled, “Reflections on the Revolution in France, and on
the Proceedings in Certain Societies in London Relative to That Event: In a
Letter Intended to Have Been Sent to a Gentleman in Paris.” The rather long
title was then trimmed to the now popular "Reflections on the Revolution in
France".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The 'Certain societies' mentioned in the original title was referring to a
revolutionary society in England which supported Protestantism as the state
religion. This was a peaceful society, not as revolutionary as its name
suggests. The name rather alludes to its admiration of the "Glorious Revolution"
in England in 1688, which deposed the Catholic monarch and replaced him with a
Protestant monarch, thus establishing the victory of parliament over the
crown. The society was also happy about the revolution in France, and supported
the National Assembly. Not just England, but every other neighbouring country
was afraid of the contagious revolution in France spreading to their land. One
has to presume that Burke was worried too. He directly attacked the
revolutionary society in England, the French National Assembly, and the
enlightenment ideas of liberty, natural rights and Constitution. Plus, the wound
left by the Gordon riots in London in 1780, an attack on the Catholics, must have
still been fresh in Burke's mind.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I present a few passages from Burke's reflection on the "Liberty, Equality,
Fraternity" movement in France, and the forming of a constitution by the
National Assembly, nullifying the monarch and his divine authority, He wrote:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"It is known; that armies have hitherto yielded a very precarious and uncertain
obedience to any senate, or popular authority; and they will least of all yield
it to an assembly which is only to have a continuance of two years. The officers
must totally lose the characteristic disposition of military men, if they see
with perfect submission and due admiration, the dominion of pleaders; especially
when they find that they have a new court to pay to an endless succession of
those pleaders; whose military policy, and the genius of whose command, (if they
should have any,) must be as uncertain as their duration is transient. In the
weakness of one kind of authority, and in the fluctuation of all, the officers
of an army will remain for some time mutinous and full of faction, until some
&lt;span class="underline"&gt;popular general&lt;/span&gt;, who understands the art of conciliating the soldiery, and who
possesses the true spirit of command, shall draw the eyes of all men upon
himself. Armies will obey him on his personal account.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A few years later, enter Napoleon Bonaparte!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is only one comparably Cassandra-like prediction, writes Christopher
Hitchens, "that I can call to mind, and that is Rosa Luxemburg’s warning to
Lenin that revolution can move swiftly from the dictatorship of a class to the
dictatorship of a party, to be followed by the dictatorship of a committee of
that party and eventually by the rule of a single man who will soon enough
dispense with that committee."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Next passage. &lt;span class="underline"&gt;Of the then French queen, Burke wrote:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"It is now sixteen or seventeen years since I saw the queen of France, then the
dauphiness, at Versailles; and surely never lighted on this orb, which she
hardly seemed to touch, a more delightful vision. I saw her just above the
horizon, decorating and cheering the elevated sphere she just began to move
in,—glittering like the morning-star, full of life, and splendour, and joy.  I
thought ten thousand swords must have leaped from their scabbards to avenge even
a look that threatened her with insult. But the age of chivalry is gone. That of
sophisters, economists, and calculators, has succeeded; and the glory of Europe
is extinguished for ever. Never, never more shall we behold that generous
loyalty to rank and sex, that proud submission, that dignified obedience, that
subordination of the heart, which kept alive, even in servitude itself, the
spirit of an exalted freedom."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span class="underline"&gt;Of the National Assembly and the constitution, Burke wrote:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"If this monster of a constitution can continue, France will be wholly governed
by the agitators in corporations, by societies in the towns formed of directors
of assignats and trustees for the sale of church lands, attornies, agents,
money-jobbers, speculators, and adventurers, composing an ignoble oligarchy,
founded on the destruction of the crown, the church, the nobility, and the
people. Here end all the deceitful dreams and visions of the equality and rights
of men."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span class="underline"&gt;Of the social contract. Burke wrote:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"It becomes a partnership not only between those who are living, but between
those who are living, those who are dead, and those who are to be born. Each
contract of each particular state is but a clause in the great primeval contract
of eternal society, linking the lower with the higher natures, connecting the
visible and invisible world, according to a fixed compact sanctioned by the
inviolable oath which holds all physical and all moral natures, each in their
appointed place."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Now let's listen to Paine's reply.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org315d71f" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org315d71f"&gt;Paine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org315d71f"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thomas Paine's reply to Burke's pamphlet is equally emphatic. The general tone
could be sampled in the paragraph below:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"As to the tragic paintings by which Mr. Burke has outraged his own imagination,
and seeks to work upon that of his readers, they are very well calculated for
theatrical representation, where facts are manufactured for the sake of show,
and accommodated to produce, through the weakness of sympathy, a weeping
effect. But Mr. Burke should recollect that he is writing history, and not
plays, and that his readers will expect truth, and not the spouting rant of
high-toned exclamation."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
and in the following paragraph as well:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"There is scarcely an epithet of abuse to be found in the English language, with
which Mr. Burke has not loaded the French Nation and the National
Assembly. Everything which rancour, prejudice, ignorance or knowledge could
suggest, is poured forth in the copious fury of near four hundred pages. In the
strain and on the plan Mr. Burke was writing, he might have written on to as
many thousands. When the tongue or the pen is let loose in a frenzy of passion,
it is the man, and not the subject, that becomes exhausted."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I include these to show how vicious ideological battles in writing was back
then. Apart from these, most other parts of Paine's reply are rather technical,
and it counters almost every major accusation made by Burke. He has defended the
revolutionary society of England, and the idea of natural and civil rights which
was then zeitgeist. Paine wrote:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Mr. Burke, on the contrary, denies that such a right exists in the nation,
either in whole or in part, or that it exists anywhere; and, what is still more
strange and marvellous, he says: "that the people of England utterly disclaim
such a right, and that they will resist the practical assertion of it with their
lives and fortunes." That men should take up arms and spend their lives and
fortunes, not to maintain their rights, but to maintain they have not rights, is
an entirely new species of discovery, and suited to the paradoxical genius of
Mr. Burke."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span class="underline"&gt;About Burke's admiration of the queen, and the disappointment in the lost
chivalry, Paine replied:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"When we see a man dramatically lamenting in a publication intended to be
believed that "The age of chivalry is gone! that The glory of Europe is
extinguished for ever! that The unbought grace of life (if anyone knows what it
is), the cheap defence of nations, the nurse of manly sentiment and heroic
enterprise is gone!" and all this because the Quixot age of chivalry nonsense is
gone, what opinion can we form of his judgement, or what regard can we pay to his
facts? In the rhapsody of his imagination he has discovered a world of wind
mills, and his sorrows are that there are no Quixots to attack them."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span class="underline"&gt;About Burke's notion of a social contract needing to be between the living,
dead and the unborn, Paine wrote:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Every age and generation must be as free to act for itself in all cases as the
age and generations which preceded it. The vanity and presumption of governing
beyond the grave is the most ridiculous and insolent of all tyrannies. Man has
no property in man; neither has any generation a property in the generations
which are to follow. The Parliament or the people of 1688, or of any other
period, had no more right to dispose of the people of the present day, or to
bind or to control them in any shape whatever, than the parliament or the people
of the present day have to dispose of, bind or control those who are to live a
hundred or a thousand years hence. Every generation is, and must be, competent
to all the purposes which its occasions require. It is the living, and not the
dead, that are to be accommodated. When man ceases to be, his power and his
wants cease with him; and having no longer any participation in the concerns of
this world, he has no longer any authority in directing who shall be its
governors, or how its government shall be organised, or how administered."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span class="underline"&gt;About society, contract and the Constitution, Paine replied:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"In casting our eyes over the world, it is extremely easy to distinguish the
governments which have arisen out of society, or out of the social compact, from
those which have not; but to place this in a clearer light than what a single
glance may afford, it will be proper to take a review of the several sources
from which governments have arisen and on which they have been founded. They may
be all comprehended under three heads. First, Superstition. Secondly,
Power. Thirdly, The common interest of society and the common rights of man. The
first was a government of priestcraft, the second of conquerors, and the third
of reason."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org2f66a0d" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org2f66a0d"&gt;Burke vs Paine - The conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org2f66a0d"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Well, if nothing has had been concluded in over 200 years, it would be hard to
conclude anything now. That is the tragedy of social sciences. At any rate, few
observations must be made.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, this exchange of words must have unveiled the general political
situation of the late 18th century you. Both of them had supporters and
followers. It certainly has affected our modern world in many ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edmund Burke is considered as the founder of conservatism now. Whether he
knew it is arguable. I suppose his writings, especially the &lt;i&gt;Reflections on
Revolutions&lt;/i&gt; has acted as an inspiration in autopsy for the conservatives. It
doesn't really help us, in this podcast episode to define Conservatism
really. Nevertheless, it is imperative to be aware of his views with all its
frailties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burke passage about the French queen might not be palatable for a reader of
21st century, but if you look around to find similarities, find it you might
quicker than you would think it might be. Hero worship is still pervasive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most curious comment made by Burke, according to me, the hardest to
comprehend is regarding the social contract needing to include the living,
dead and the unborn. Perhaps, we are reading it in an entirely different
circumstances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burke's triumph is in the Cassandra like prediction of the a powerful
military general. That was eerily exact!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thomas Paine is not considered the father of liberalism, but it is impossible
to study or analyse the idea of liberty without Paine. It is as simple as
that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
With that, let's move on to the 19th century, where Classical Liberalism and
Conservatism took its real shape.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org287ff37" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org287ff37"&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org287ff37"&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arguably, Christopher Hitchens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflections on Revolution in France, Edmund Burke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rights of Man, Thomas Paine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common Sense, Thomas Paine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Political Ideologies : An Introduction, Andrew Heywood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The French Revolution, William Doyle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>podcast</category><category>politics</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/pi_four/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>പയ്യന് ബ്യാടിയെ കിട്ടി</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/payyanubaddiekitti/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
ആ… വല്യമ്മേ!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ആരാ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഞാനാ പയ്യൻ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഏത് പയ്യൻ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എൻ ആർ ഐ പയ്യൻ 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അതാരാ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഞാനാ വല്യമ്മേ, ഡെസ്സിക്കേറ്റഡ് കോകോനട്ട്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ആഹ്… പറ മോനേ, എന്തൊക്കെയുണ്ട് വിശേഷം?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അല്ല, ഒരു ചെറിയ അപ്ഡേറ്റ് ഉണ്ട്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എന്താത് ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എനിക്ക് ബ്യാടി സെറ്റായി.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ബാടിയോ, നിനക്കോ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ബാടിയല്ല വല്യമ്മേ. ബ്യാടി. ചിക്ക്. കാമുകി. പ്രേമഭാജനം.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അതുശരി, കൊടുകൈ! 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
താൻഗ്യു വല്യമ്മേ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
സെർട്ടിഫൈഡ് ആണോ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അതെ വല്യമ്മേ. 9/10.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
പത്തുശതമാനം മാഗ്പൈക്കോ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ബർമിംഗ്ഹമിലാണ് പഠിച്ചത് 
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
വേറെ കുഴപ്പങ്ങളെന്തെങ്കിലും ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഇല്ല്യ, തനി മദിരാക്ഷി.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അപ്പോൾ മലയാളം ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
മദിരാസിയല്ല വല്യമ്മേ. &lt;br&gt;
മതിമോഹനശുഭനർത്തനമാടുന്നയീ മഹിത &lt;br&gt;
മമ മുന്നിൽ നിന്ന മലയാള കവിത.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കാഞ്ചനകാഞ്ചി കുലുക്കിക്കുലുക്കിയാണോ മുന്നിൽ വന്നത്?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അതെ വല്യമ്മേ! വന്നപാടെ ഒരു ചോദ്യം.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എന്താരാഞ്ഞു?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
(&lt;i&gt;നിശബ്ദത&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;പരമാവധി നിശബ്ദത&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;നിങ്ങൾ മലയാളിയാണോ?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
.&lt;br&gt;
(&lt;i&gt;നിശബ്ദത&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;പരമാവധി നിശബ്ദത&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
സ്വസ്തി. നിന്റെ കണ്ണുകളിലെ അപ്പോഴത്തെ വെള്ളപൊക്കം ഞാനൊന്നൂഹിച്ചോട്ടെ? അനശ്വര പ്രേമകഥകൾ
നമ്മളിതിനുമുൻപും കേട്ടിട്ടില്ലേ?  മൈത്രേയി യജ്ഞവൽക്കനോടും, ജാനകി രമണനോടും, സത്യഭാമ സൂത്രധാരനോടും,
സാറാമ്മ കേശവൻനായരോടും ചോദിച്ചത് '&lt;i&gt;നിങ്ങൾ മലയാളിയാണോ&lt;/i&gt;' എന്നല്ലേ?. ചരിത്രാവർത്തനത്തിൽ
വിരസതകണ്ടെത്താനാവില്ല പയ്യൻ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
പരമാർത്ഥത്തിന്റെ താരാട്ട് വല്യമ്മേ, പക്ഷെ എനിക്കുറക്കം വരുന്നില്ല.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എന്നിട്ട് നീ എന്ത് പറഞ്ഞു?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അതെ, ഞാൻ തന്നെ മലയാളി, എന്ന് പറയുന്നതിൽ ശകലം ശുംഭത്തരം കളിയാടുന്നല്ലോ വല്യമ്മേ. അവൾ അത്
എങ്ങനെയോ തിരിച്ചറിഞ്ഞുകഴിഞ്ഞിരിക്കുന്നു. അവളുടെ ഞരമ്പുകളിൽ ഉടനെ ചോര തിളപ്പിക്കേണ്ടത്
നിമിഷധർമ്മാണ്ണെന്ന് എന്റെ ഷഷ്ഠേന്ദ്രിയം വിശദീകരിച്ചു. ഉൾകീശയിൽ നിന്നും ഞാൻ കരുതിവച്ചിരുന്ന
'റിസ്സ്' പുറത്തെടുത്ത് നാലായിതുറന്നു. എന്നിട്ടിങ്ങനെ മൊഴിഞ്ഞു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
തനികൈരളീരക്തമാംസനിബദ്ധവിഗ്രഹസാക്ഷാത്കാരം
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ബ്യാടിയുടെ കാലൊന്ന് പതറി. എന്റെ കണ്ണുകളിലെ വെള്ളപൊക്കം അവൾ തെല്ലുനേരത്തേക്ക്
കടമെടുത്തു. ജീവിതത്തിൽ സുഖദുഃഖങ്ങളുടെ ജക്സ്റ്റപൊസിഷൻ എന്താണെന്നറിയാൻ നാലർദ്ധനിമീലിതാക്ഷികൾ
തലങ്ങും വിലങ്ങും തിരഞ്ഞു. തമ്മിലെ അന്തരം അജഗജാന്തരമല്ലെന്ന് മനസ്സിലാക്കിത്തുടങ്ങിയ ഞങ്ങളുടെ ഹൃദയങ്ങൾ
ഝംഝനനാദത്തോടെ മിടിച്ചുതുടങ്ങി. ചുണ്ടുകൾ മിണ്ടിത്തുടങ്ങി. പദങ്ങൾ ഉണർന്നു. പാദങ്ങൾ ചലിച്ചു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഏതായിരുന്നു ക്ലബ് ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
സ്ത്രമാഷ്, വല്യമ്മേ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
സബാഷ് 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കുട്ടിയുടെ ഗോ-ട്ടു?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഇനിസ്സ് ആൻഡ് ഗൺ ലാഗാ
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അവസാനം വരെയും?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അല്ല വല്യമ്മേ. ഇടയ്ക്കെവിടെയോ വച്ച് സ്‌പൈസ്‌ഡ്‌ റം വിത്ത് ജിഞ്ചർ യേലിലേക്ക് മാറുന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ക്യൂറിയോസേർ, കണ്ടമാനം ക്യൂറിയോസേർ. &lt;br&gt;
നീ ഇപ്പോഴും ഗിന്നസ്സ് തന്നെ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഹിഹി 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ങ്ഹാ, എന്നിട്ട് ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
നൃത്തസർഗ്ഗപ്രക്രിയയിൽ ഞങ്ങൾ തകർത്താടി. വീ വിൽ റോക്ക് യൂവിൽ തുടങ്ങി, ലോ ലോ ലോ ലോ ലോ വരയ്ക്കും
ഞങ്ങൾ അനർഗ്ഗളം ഒഴുകിയാടിത്തിമിർത്തു. അവസാനം, വൺ കിസ്സ് ഈസ് ഓൾ ഇറ്റ് ടേയ്ക്സിൽ ഞങ്ങളുടെ തലയൊന്ന്
കൂട്ടിമുട്ടി. പിന്നെ…, ഓർമ്മകൾ തീവണ്ടിയിൽ പച്ചക്കൊടി കാണിക്കുന്ന വെള്ളവസ്ത്രധാരിയെപ്പോലെ ദൂരെ
മറഞ്ഞു. X എന്ന ചിഹ്നവും. രാവിലെ അവളുടെ ഫോണിൽ കുക്കുടം കൊഞ്ചുന്നത് കേട്ടാണുണർന്നത്. എന്റെ ഫോൺ ഇന്നലെ
രാത്രിതന്നെ ചത്തിരുന്നു വല്യമ്മേ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
നിന്റെ പരാജയങ്ങളെ ഇങ്ങനെ നഗ്നസത്യങ്ങളായി വിളിച്ചുപറയാതിരിക്കൂ പയ്യൻ. നിലനിൽപ്പ് തന്നെ പഴയകാല
വ്യക്തിത്വത്തിന്റെ അവശിഷ്ടങ്ങളല്ലേ? റീചാർജ് ചെയ്താൽ വീണ്ടും ഉപയോഗിക്കാവുന്നതല്ലേ ഉള്ളൂ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ആട്ടെ, കുട്ടിയേതാ മതം ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
സയൻസ്സ്, വല്യമ്മേ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
നമ്മുടെ ജാതിയാണോ ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അല്ല, വല്യമ്മേ, നാച്ചുറൽ സയൻസ്സാണ്. ഭൗതികശാസ്ത്രം.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഓഹോ, ഭേഷ്!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ശേഷം കണ്ടിരുന്നോ ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
നാളെ വീണ്ടും വല്യമ്മേ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എന്താ സ്പെഷ്യൽ ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
വോൾട്ടർ ലൂയിൻന്റെ "ഫോർ ദി ലവ് ഓഫ് ഫിസിക്സ്" ലെക്ചർ, ആൻഡ് ചിൽ 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അവളുടെ പ്രേരണ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഓ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എന്താ നിന്റെ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
മുരിങ്ങക്കായ സാമ്പാർ, കാരറ്റ്-ബീൻസ് ഉപ്പേരി, പരിപ്പും നെയ്യും, പപ്പടം, ചോറ്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
തേങ്ങ അരച്ചുചേർത്താണോ ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അല്ല വല്യമ്മേ, ഡെസ്സിക്കേറ്റഡ് കോകോനട്ട്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഹഹഹഹ്ഹഹ്ഹ. എന്നാ ശെരി, സീരിയൽ സമയമായി.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
സീരിയലേതാ വല്യമ്മേ ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
അറ്റൻബറോന്റെ "ആർ പ്ലാനറ്റ്". സീസൺ 2, എപ്പിസോഡ് 3.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
നൈസ്. വല്യച്ഛൻ ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ചായ ഉണ്ടാക്കാൻ പോയതാണ്, ദാ വരുന്നുണ്ട്. സെ നമസ്‌തെ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഹലോ മിസ്റ്റർ വല്യച്ഛൻ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
(&lt;i&gt;പിന്നണിയിൽ വല്യച്ഛൻ വല്യമ്മയോട്‌ ആരാണെന്ന് ചോദിക്കുന്നു. ഡെസ്സിക്കേറ്റഡ് കോകോനട്ട് പയ്യനാണെന്ന് വല്യമ്മ വാക്ക് നൽകുന്നു&lt;/i&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഹലോ പയ്യൻ, എന്താണ് വിശേഷം?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എനിക്ക് ബ്യാടി സെറ്റായി വല്യച്ഛൻ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ബാടിയോ, നിനക്കോ?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ബാടിയല്ല. ബ്യാടി. ചിക്ക്. കാമുകി. പ്രേമഭാജനം.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ശുഭം 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>comedy</category><category>payyan</category><category>satire</category><category>പയ്യൻ</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/payyanubaddiekitti/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 18:25:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Political Ideologies - Age of Enlightenment</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/pi_three/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
"Man was born" free, and he is everywhere in chains", Rousseau, wrote in his book, 'The social contract'
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We stopped our previous episode with a promise to find links between the French
Revolution and Political Ideologies. That's exactly what we are craving
today. To answer the gargantuan three letter question, 'Why'? To see if there
had been a change in western thought prior to the French revolution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Welcome to Hitchens' Razor!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the first episode of this series, we performed a somersault recap of world
history to arrive at the main event - the social big bang as I like to call it;
the French Revolution of the 18th century CE.  In the second episode, we tried
to deconstruct the story of the revolution. In both these episodes, we journeyed
through the Feudal system, where power was based on the ownership of the land;
to the ancien regime, where power was inherited or god-given, and finally the
power of the constitution. The society was then classified into Nobles, Clergy
and Everyone else. All three orders were subjected to a monarch, who had the
divine right to rule. Then suddenly the status quo vanished, the heads of
monarchy and royalty started rolling on the floor. Well, 'suddenly' is a word
best used in hindsight. In reality, it was not all that sudden, was it?  It
takes many years to brew revolutions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Before we dive in to the topic, I would like cite our thanks:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An introduction to political philosophy, by Jonathan Wolff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lecture videos by Professor Arthur Holmes, Wheaton College.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The myth of the state by Ernst Cassirer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The French Revolution by George Lefebvre&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Philosophy of science by Samir Okasha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liberalism by Michael Freeden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Democracy by Bernard Crick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The social contract by Jean-Jacques Rousseau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So, what causes revolutions? In other words, what fails to keep societies stable
and resilient? &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; In a stable society, the economic cycle turns smoothly,
people produce, earn, pay taxes, and still have sufficient income left to
support themselves and their families. The taxes paid by the populace reach the
ruler, who distributes it for various purposes. One of them being the protection
of its people. This equilibrium is maintained by the institutions of the land -
the bureaucracy, military, religion etc. What causes in-equilibrium then?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Poverty is the simplest explanation, but in truth that alone isn't the
reason. It is rather curious an observation that revolutions occur more often in
middle-income countries than in the very poorest nations. French revolution
happened when the peasants in France were better off than peasants in
Russia. Also, like we mentioned in the previous episode, the French Revolution
had three parts to it: the aristocratic, the bourgeoisie, and the popular
revolutions. It seems that revolutions happen when significant portions of the
elites, and the military defect or stand aside instead of defending the old
regime. Apart from this, here are some reasons according to Goldstone:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demographic changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International relations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flatlining of economy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inequality, discrimination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personalist regimes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So why did the Kingdom of France fail? That is a bait we wouldn't dare to take
today. Instead we would try to generalise the causes of revolutions, not just in
France, but other countries of the west as well. Though the consensus is rather
stable at the inexplicable nature of the causation of revolutions, there was a
point in one of our previous episodes where I tried to empathise with the common
people of Europe in the middle ages. I invite you to join me in thinking… &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Think about a generation which had witnessed their mothers, sisters and grand
mothers burnt at stake; their brothers and fathers hanged, drawn and
quartered. A generation that was forced into becoming professional beggars. And
the only explanation available for all these misery was religion; of their
present sufferings being rewarded in another world, in another life. But aren't
we pattern seeking animals? and when we identify patterns don't we have the
tendency to act on it?  &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; I think it was inevitable, the rulers of the
western world was begging for a change, for a revolution."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That's our empathy, but the bigger question is, 'Did the western thought change
at some point'? &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; How?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgb2085f5" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgb2085f5"&gt;Land&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgb2085f5"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps we could use the classification of society in the middle ages to explain
the transition in thought process at each level. We start with land. Lefebvre
writes, "Land was virtually the only source of income in an aristocratic world
where priests and nobles were royal subjects. The state had all the sovereign
powers. The Lords had authority over their own peasants. Serfdom existed in
regions of western Europe. Its subjects were bound to the land, which was
strictly limited to rights of inheritance. The economy was stagnant. Production
was limited by scarcity, rules, and war. People sough assistance and protection
of family and communities, and parish. Competition in the market was restricted
with controls.  Extra work or pro-activeness fetched no reward because the
system shackled it.  Advertisements were useless, people waited for clients to
approach them, and so they sold very little for high prices. Taxes, hierarchy,
and authority remained in the society. Along with this the lower classes
continued to hold superstitious beliefs in magic, sorcery, astrology, and
alchemy."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The bourgeoisie didn't see much hope in this static society. So, they ventured
beyond their land.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgb409b98" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgb409b98"&gt;Beyond Land&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgb409b98"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After the barbarian conquests, Europeans forayed into invasion mode. They
travelled far and wide to different continents and brought back all kinds of
treasures. The contagious example of material success encouraged all those who
judged themselves capable of enjoying rewards offered during this life
itself. They returned home rich. Money bought them privileges, and eventually
power, and changes followed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each child started to demand their rightful inheritance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disintegration of family and traditional groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;life in a city started sprouting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;members classified based on their residence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;personal mobility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;expanding industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adventure, risk and rewards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dynamic and unstable society in which power was based on money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It added glamour to this life and obscured the after life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org27d8e29" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org27d8e29"&gt;Scientific Revolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org27d8e29"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When science arrived at the scene, the hitherto magical explanation of the
universe started to wane, for science's intention was to condense the whole
universe to a series of equations, and scientists were becoming increasingly
successful at this.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"One of the important innovations in this era" writes Lefebvre, "was the ability
to fix positions geographically, which was essential for navigation as well as
to the measurement of globe and cartography(that is the art of making maps or
charts). New nautical instruments such as the compass, the sextant were
invented, and Borda's circle determined latitudes. Construction of the
chronometer and maritime clocks and basic establishment of astronomical charts
meant that longitudes could be calculated rather than simply estimated. These
were revolutionary advances."  Science enabled the discovery and control of
natural forces.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The scientific worldview drastically changed when the Polish astronomer Nicolas
Copernicus claimed that is sun is the centre of the universe, not
earth. Johannes Kepler and Galileo Galilei carried the baton forward. Kepler
accepted the Copernican view and improved it by claiming the planetary bodies
revolved in ellipses than in circles. He also calculated the speed of this
motion. Galileo pointed his telescope at heavens and found interesting
phenomena. He also argued against the Aristotelian theory that heavier objects
falls faster than lighter ones, saying all bodies will fall towards earth at the
same rate if not for the air resistance they feel. He used the language of
Mathematics to explain physical things. He also emphasised testing out
hypothesis experimentally. The scientific revolution continued with Rene
Descartes's in the 17th century with his mechanical philosophy where he
explained the physical world in terms of particles interacting and colliding
with one another. After Descartes, Issac Newton published the Mathematical
Principles of Natural Philosophy in the late 17th century which improved
Cartesian theory with great accuracy. His three laws seemed to explain all
observable phenomena in the world. He also invented the mathematical technique
called Calculus to explain the theory. He was able to prove Kepler's laws of
planetary motion, and Galileo's law of free fall using his theory. Differential
and integral Calculus was developed by Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz in parallel to
Newton.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgfc9e662" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgfc9e662"&gt;Age of Enlightenment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgfc9e662"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We cannot escape the topic of philosophy when we are trying to answer the
question, 'Why'.  With Philosophy comes its philosophers, and we are going to
have a tryst with some of the philosophers of the age of enlightenment, and
dance our way through the major thoughts and ideas of the age. But first, let's
address the elephant in the room, God. Omnipotent is the claim, and omnipresent
is this mammoth in the history books of philosophy. Pray, we shall dare to seek
an explanation of the societal transformation by starting God on the bench. It
is thus, with utmost convenience, that we discard the divine intervention in our
search for the answer. You see, most of our philosophers were believers and
theologians, but please remember that they arrived and departed before Charles
Darwin. Fair play to them, there has had been a Galapagos sized gap in their
head that had to be filled, which they did, with god, with questions about body
and mind, liberty, equality, justice, morality, ethics, social contract, natural
rights, happiness, scientific rationalism, physics, metaphysics, economic
prosperity, free markets and so on and so forth.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We had a brief brushing with physics in the previous section, and now, to
metaphysics. It seems &lt;i&gt;meta&lt;/i&gt; in ancient Greek meant ‘after’. So ‘metaphysics’,
yes…, after physics. Physics is about things that change; the metaphysics is
about things that don’t change. So, natural science investigates things in this
world or universe which tend to change or move or transform, which can be
sensed, observed, experimented upon, or experienced, whereas, metaphysics
transcends experience. It concerns mind where physics is concerned with
body. And that is philosophy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The two dominant branches of western philosophy during the age of enlightenment
are called the Empiricism and Rationalism. Interestingly, there is an
intersection of these two schools of thought and further advancement of western
philosophy from that point. Empiricism comes from &lt;i&gt;empeiria&lt;/i&gt; meaning
"experience; mere experience or practice without knowledge. Rationalism, on the
other hand comes from &lt;i&gt;reason&lt;/i&gt;. Either way, the two questions that really
matters in political philosophy are: 'Who gets what', and 'says who'? The first
is about the distribution of goods, and of rights and liberties. The second
question concerns the distribution of Political power. One task for the
political philosopher is to determine the correct balance between autonomy and
authority.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Of the two major factions or western philosophy, Empiricism began with Francis
Bacon(1561-1626). &lt;i&gt;'Knowledge is power'&lt;/i&gt;, is his famous dictum. He emphasised on
the need for seeking evidence to prove things. A methodical approach to the
investigation of the nature and limits of human mind and then to draw
consequences for how we should regulate our beliefs and actions. Empiricists
believed that an idea in the mind that can be traced back to some particular
experience. Ideas come from senses or sense-impressions of the past.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Rene Descartes(1596-1650), is believed to be the originator of rationalism. &lt;i&gt;'I
think, therefore I am'&lt;/i&gt;, is his famous dictum. Rationalists believed that ideas
are innate, it came from within. They used deductive reasoning to explain things
using axioms as the premise, and deduction as the method to derive conclusions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Before we go any further, a friendly reminder on why people had to think about
these things. We have already touched upon the way of life in the ancien regime,
of religious dogmas, of superstitious beliefs in magic, sorcery, astrology, and
alchemy. The intellectual exercises of the age of enlightenment were not merely
a departure from the status quo, but a discontinuity in the way of life
itself. There was a break in the continuity of thoughts and debates from the
medieval ages. Ernst Cassirer has some interesting observations in his book &lt;i&gt;'The
myth of the state'&lt;/i&gt; where he says "All the progress made by the Renaissance and
the Reformation were counterbalanced by the loss of unity and inner harmony of
the medieval culture, especially ethical foundation of the medieval civilization
was seriously affected. The heliocentric system deprived man of his privileged
condition. He became, as it were, an exile in the infinite universe. The cracks
formed in Christianity were irreparable. Only Reason, which is autonomous and
self-dependent could bring back the ethics and harmony."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Cassirer also writes that political theories of the age of enlightenment was a
rejuvenation of Stoic ideas. Stoicism is from the Greek and Roman period which
is capsuled in the phrase &lt;i&gt;'Virtue is its own reward'&lt;/i&gt;. Morality and happiness is
derived from following virtues like wisdom, courage, controlling emotions,
justice, and living in accordance with nature. All these political theories have
a common metaphysical background than a theological one. This is backed by
mathematics and reasoning.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In a way, writes Milan Zafirovski in his book &lt;i&gt;The Enlightenment and Its Effects
on Modern Society&lt;/i&gt;, "the Enlightenment operates as the composite process of
intellectual destruction and deconstruction of the values and institutions of
the ancien regime as a total social system and of creation or projection of
those of a new society. The inner logic, essential process, and ultimate outcome
of the Enlightenment are the destruction of old oppressive, theocratic,
irrational, and inhumane social values and institutions, and the creation of
new democratic, secular, rational, and humane ones through human reason or, as
Immanuel Kant put it, “dare to think.”
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The famous words from American Declaration of Independence: "All men are created
equal with certain unalienable rights to life, liberty and pursuit of
happiness". To secure these rights, governments are instituted among men,
deriving their just powers from the consent of the governed", are the effects of
these ideas. That was the noticeable change; Ideas started to have
consequences. Revolutions are the prime examples of that. I think with the
formation of parliaments, and republics in Europe and North America, and the
social revolution of France, we witnessed a reciprocity of thoughts and actions.
Most of these ideas were repeated from the past, but now these ideas were forged
into weapons. The attack became direct. Their is no veiled disguise or use of
abstract terms anymore. Straight to the point. Ecrasez l'infâme, said Voltaire,
"Crush the loathsome thing", and he was referring to the Roman Catholic Church.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
With that we move on to Hobbes, Locke and Rousseau. Thomas Hobbes(1588-1679) is
most famous for his book Leviathan, in which he invites the reader to travel to
a hypothetical world where there is no civilisation or societies. It is called
the state of nature. In the state of nature there are no rules, or morals, or
ethics attached to the people. The question is then to ask how and why did that
change? It is a thought experiment similar to parents reprimanding children for
wasting food by saying, 'you will understand the value of it in its absence'.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Hobbes was rather pessimistic about life of human in the state of nature. He was
inspired by Galileo's principle of conservation of motion, that is things will
remain in motion unless acted upon by a force. Hobbes used this premise in a
social context and put forth the idea of life is always in motion, and never
without felicity. Felicity means the continuous success in achieving the objects
of desire. Felicity, when combined with the scarcity of resources in the world
would cause conflicts, which will eventually turn into war. He further argues
that when people acquire possessions, they acquire fear as well. They will try
to protect their possessions from thieves and invaders, and thus are constantly
on guard. Either that, or they are just afraid of a preemptive, unprovoked
attack. Hobbes also assumes that human beings are equal by nature. So he says,
any human being can kill another either by brute strength, or by technique or
weapons, or forming a team against another. In his explanation, the power that
someone possesses today is a means to obtain some future good for themselves. In
other words, power today helps to achieve desires of the future, so people will
always seek power over others. Hence, in the state of nature nothing can be
unjust, every person has the liberty to act as they think fit to preserve their
'right of nature', so there is no place or reason for morality. Hobbes's
solution is to have a sovereign who would put laws in place and punish people
who wouldn't obey those.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Paraphrasing his famous paragraph from Leviathan,
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Whatsoever therefore is consequent to a time of war, where every man is Enemy
to every man; the same is consequent to the time, wherein men live without other
security, than what their own strength, and their own invention shall furnish
them with all. In such condition, there is no place for Industry; because the
fruit thereof is uncertain; and consequently no Culture of the Earth; no
Navigation, nor use of the commodities that may be imported by Sea; no
commodious Building; no Instruments of moving, and removing such things as
require much force; no Knowledge of the face of the Earth; no account of Time;
no Arts; no Letters; no Society; and which is worst of all, continue all in
fear, and danger of violent death; And the life of man…, solitary, poor,
nasty, brutish, and short.”
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
John Locke(1632-1704) disagreed with Hobbes's idea in many parts, but Locke's
counter arguments had God factor in it as the reason why no one has natural
right to harm another in his life. Interestingly, Locke says that in the state
of nature, there will be a natural right held by each to punish those who harm
another person's life, liberty or property. Right to punish is seen different
from the right to self defence, which is claimed as a right by Hobbes. Locke
thinks that moral law-abiding citizens will come together with the victim to
bring the villain to justice. One key difference is that Locke thinks there will
be no deep scarcity of goods in the world.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Locke assumes that human beings are naturally free, equal, and independent. This
means that they are not naturally under the authority of any other person.
Accordingly, Locke concluded that the only way of coming under another person's
authority was to give that person your consent punishment. This holds, for
Locke, whether the person claiming authority is another private individual or
the sovereign. Thus the sovereign, who claims authority over you, has no right
to that authority unless you have voluntarily put yourself in this position
through your own consent.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Jean-Jacques Rousseau(1712-1778) agrees with Locke about Hobbes being wrong of
extreme scarcity in the state of nature, but disagrees about the ideas of
morality as the motivation for goodness in the state of nature. Instead he
proposes natural pity or compassion as the element that will rescue humanity
from killing each other.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Essentially, for the social contract theorists after Hobbes, the state is
justified if, but only if, every individual over which it claims authority has
consented. Consent, that is keyword. That's probably what caused the
discontinuity in the hitherto way of life. Well, I would like to leave you with
few questions:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you think of life in the state of nature if you were in it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are your natural rights?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are you thoughts on possessions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What binds an individual to a state?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you give consent?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The intention of this episode is to introduce the alternate thoughts before the
French Revolution which could have been its possible causation. We have
mentioned a few names, and omitted many more. But names are not interesting to
us, it's the ideas and stories that enthral us.  There is more to cover from
this part of history, but an episode's space is rather constrained. It's perhaps
a travesty to omit &lt;i&gt;The Prince&lt;/i&gt; by Niccolo Machiavelli(1469-1527) while
discussing alternate thoughts and ideas. Enlightened despotism or absolutism was
also skipped. The idea where monarch agrees that royal power does not come from
divine right but from a social contract whereby a despot was entrusted with the
power to govern through a social contract in lieu of any other governments. We
didn't speak much about collection of knowledge in Encyclopedia, which happened
in this era. The original feminist Mary Wollstonecraft lived in this era. Much,
much more.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the next episode we discuss the terminologies in Political Ideologies, but
for now, I must leave you and this episode with the following quote by the great
German philosopher Immanuel Kant, about the French Revolution:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
"Such an event," he said, does not consist in important deeds or
misdeeds of men, whereby, what had been great, became little among men, or what
had been little, became great, and . . . old glorious political edifices
disappeared, whereas, in their stead, other ones grew out of the ground.  No;
nothing of the kind! … The revolution of an ingenious people which we have
lived to see, may succeed or fail. It may be filled with such calamities and
atrocities that a righteous man, even if he could be sure to carry it out
luckily, never would decide to repeat the experiment at such a high price. In
spite of all this such a revolution finds, in the minds of all spectators, a
sympathy very near to enthusiasm. . . . Such a phenomenon in the history of
mankind can never be forgotten; because it proves that in human nature there
exists an inclination and disposition to the better which no politician ever
could have been able to predict by summing up the course of former events."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>podcast</category><category>politics</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/pi_three/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Political Ideologies - The French Revolution</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/pi_two/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
"On the morning of July 14, 1789, a crowd of Parisian workers set out to attack
the royal prison of the Bastille. Joined by deserting soldiers who brought
cannons, and ignored by Royal Army troops camped nearby, the crowds forced their
way into the fortress by late afternoon, killing the governor and parading his
head on a pike. That evening King Louis XVI reportedly asked a duke, "is this a
revolt?" To which the duke replied: "No Sire, it is a revolution"" – excerpt
from J. A. Goldstone's book, Revolutions, A Very Short Introduction.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the second episode of this series, we continue to blend into our topic of
Political Ideologies through French Revolution. Hope is to present a succinct
summary of the events, and then proceed to ask the mammoth question, 'Why?'
Welcome to Hitchens' Razor!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Someone had noticed that it is hard to talk about the French Revolution, not for
the lack of resources, because there is a plethora of it. So, before we begin
the revolution, may I regurgitate our gratefulness to the following authors for
their great work on the topic, which has immensely helped us to tell the tale.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Georges Lefebvre, The French Revolution, translated to English by Elizabeth Moss Evanson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;William Doyle, The French Revolution, a VSI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jack Goldstone, Revolutions VSI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
and a shout out to Jawaharlal Nehru for 'The Glimpses of World History', and
H.G.Wells as well for 'A Short History of the World'.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Although the narrative is simplified to be retold as a lucid story, there are
many places where we have directly quoted from some of the above authors without
saying so. We hope to leech on your ample-supple magnanimity to forgive us.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Shall we?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org4885051" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org4885051"&gt;The Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org4885051"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Our story begins in 18th century of the Common Era.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
France's attempt to remain a global super force meant waging war with other
kingdoms. They fought all over the world, at both land and the sea, in America,
in Asia, and in native Europe. Engaging in relentless war means destruction;
destruction calls for rebuilding; rebuilding costs money. During hard times,
money demands either financial discipline or bankruptcy. For France, it was the
latter. They were running out of money. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
How did the French fund these wars in the first place? Well, the Finance
minister borrowed money from Freemason banks and wealthy individual financiers
of Europe. Wait, was there a system of government? Yes! It is what we now call
the &lt;i&gt;ancien regime&lt;/i&gt;. Under &lt;i&gt;ancien regime&lt;/i&gt; the French society was then
classified into three orders: The nobles(wealthy and powerful), The clergy(God
people), and the Third Estate, i.e. everyone else. &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; Geographically, France
was divided into provinces, and there were courts or &lt;i&gt;parlements&lt;/i&gt; for each
province. The parlements were judicial bodies with around 1100 judges
nationwide. The members of the parlements were aristocrats or nobles who had
bought or inherited their offices, and were independent of the king. They
wielded decision making powers on a wide range of subjects. Apart from this, the
king had his ministers to take care of the kingdom's affairs. Okay, back to
funding wars. For France, supporting the American war of Independence to defeat
the British was dear. They had availed loans to enable the military, and
borrowed even more money to pay off the arrears. &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; Such was the deficit in
August 1786, the Finance minister sent a letter to the king mentioning the need
for a state reform. It was first of its kind act for France. Things turned worse
in the following year; so much that in March 1788 the first budget of the old
regime was needed to be drafted. Oddly enough, this was also the last budget of
the old regime. It estimated a 20% deficit at 126 million livres. More than half
of the expenditures were attributed to paying debts alone. &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; The taxes in
the country was already high, so raising taxes further to clear the arrears was
out of the question. There existed a solution to the problem though, that is to
bring equality of taxation for different classes of people and provinces of the
country. &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; And that's how it all began!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Shall we move on from the state of economics to the state of people? French
revolution could be broadly divided into three stages. The Aristocratic
revolution, the Bourgeoisie revolution, and the Popular revolution. We shall
begin with the Aristocracy's quarrel, that is the Nobles' and Clergy's quarrel
with their king.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the verge of bankruptcy, the finance minister proposed new measures to raise
funds. This included:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A direct land tax upon all landowners without any exception&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other taxes to be shared out without distinction as to order or class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freeing the grain trade from all controls, by abolishing internal customs barriers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asking clergy to clear its debt by selling the Church's manorial rights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The good minister thought that financial stability would strengthen his king's
royal power, and reduce the opposition from parlements. The King Louis VI was a
weak monarch; &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; he had very little power and control over the country's
affairs. He was considered almost a laughing stock of his courtiers and all
those who had heard the stories. Aware of this status, the finance minister used
indirect methods to get the tax reforms done. He convoked a meeting with the
representatives of aristocrats and the clergy, also known as the Assembly of
Notables to discuss the reforms. He expected the Notables to agree to the
changes because of the economic condition of their kingdom. But this move
backfired, as it amplified the frailties of the king, and it angered the
Notables even more, as they thought it was an attack on their powers and
rights. They rejected the proposal and after some internal politics the finance
minster was dismissed. The replacement minister soothed the aristocracy by
retracting the proposal, and instead offered to increase the stamp duty. But the
Notables and the parlements rejected the new tax proposal as well, because this
decision was not in their power, but was to be made by the wider group called
Estates-General or the States-General representatives of France.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The debt remained, and the new finance minister was now desperate to raise
money. Uncertain of the support from the parlements and aristocracy, he had the
King pass an edict as a royal order superseding any opposition. Nevertheless,
opposition duly came from a duke, and the duke was exiled by the King in
retaliation.  The parlements and lower tribunals and the aristocrats promptly
protested, which turned violent at places. Tit for tat continued as the King
started showing hints of despotism. The treasury was almost empty at this point
amidst the mayhem, and the King finally gave away and dismissed the Finance
minister again. The consensus pointed to the convocation of Estates-General for
any tax related decision making. Like before, that is in 1614, the convocation
was to have three orders representing the classification of the French society;
The clergy, The nobles, and the Third Estate.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What you have heard until now is the revolution that happened in the
background. The Aristocratic Revolution! The Nobles and Clergy against the
monarch. The second part, which you are about to hear is called the Bourgeoisie
Revolution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The Third Estate, that is everyone else also contained the bourgeoisie. We have
spoken a great deal about the rise of the middle class, i.e. the bourgeoisie in
the previous episode. The news of gathering of the Estates-General sent tremors
of excitement through the members of the Third Estate. Until then, they have had
not seen much need for opposing the two classes above them. Suddenly the mood
shifted. Many associations sprung up in this time - academies, agricultural
societies, philanthropic groups, reading circles. They sought equality in the
society thorough arguments of reason and natural right. Equality of taxation,
and voting by heads rather than order was their major demands. Of course, the
burden of the proposed new taxes fell disproportionately on the shoulders of
third estate, when compared to the clergy and the nobles. Meanwhile the Nobles
and the Clergy assured of their birth and divine rights, demanded a vote at the
this meeting. Since Estates-General voted by order than by head, any two estates
could outvote a third. This arrangement naturally favoured the upper
classes. &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; The mood of aristocracy during the French revolution is captured
in this extract of a letter sent to the king by the royal princes.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://mindtoilet.com/galleries/lefebvre.jpeg" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Estates-General. France was all set for the rendezvous. A hotel was arranged for
the meetings of the clergy and the nobility. A big national hall was arranged
for the third estate to meet. All party meetings were to be held in a large room
nearby. The nobles and clergy dressed in full regalia were seated on elevated
platforms, whereas the third estate representatives dressed in black were seated
on chairs at the floor level. On 5th May 1789, the proceedings began with a
brief speech by the king. Then the finance minister harangued the audience,
speaking at length about the financial situation with all sorts of boring
details. He mentioned the proposed improvements of the situation, but omitted
the subject of constitutional reforms, which everyone was desperate to hear. But
he mentioned the voting would happen by order as before. There were serious
opposition to this, but at that time the representatives didn't know each other
well, so they proceeded with caution, and a delaying tactic was used. Stalemate
continued where each order discussed further action in their allocated
places. At the beginning, the Third Estate had taken a new name for itself;
communes or, Commons. Not many knew that word evoked a vague memory of popular
resistance to the feudal lords. For the Commons, they simply refused to be
relegated to the third rank.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Few days later, the nobility, strong on its belief, announced themselves as a
separate order. The Clergy meanwhile was in trouble because a large proportion
of the parish church or the district church priests, supported the Commons. The
bishops sensed imminent defection of the parish priests. So they requested the
king to intervene. The King asked the conferences to be resumed at the common
place, in the presence of his ministers. The finance minister further said that
if no agreement could be reached, then the king's decision would be final. This
put the Commons in a difficult position, but ironically the nobility rejected
that royal arbitration proposal.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The Commons now invited privileged members to join them. Many parish priests
did, but not one noble. With the new members the Third Estate's name was again
changed to National Assembly. They demanded that all three classes be merged and
voting shall be done by heads instead of order. They further claimed the power
to consent to taxation. The nobility now ended their resistance towards the king
and begged him to put the Third Estate back in line. But by now the majority of
the clergy declared in favour of merging the three orders. Finally the finance
minister came out and proposed equality of taxation and voting by heads. The
King still hesitated. One fine day, the National Assembly, formerly known as the
Commons, formerly known as the Third Estate discovered that the national hall
where they met regularly to discuss their affairs was closed without any notice
or warning. Certainly not defeated yet, they immediately convened in a Tennis
court nearby, and took an oath to give France a constitution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The king now disregarding his Finance minister, came up with his own
declarations guaranteeing a constitutional system, civil liberty etc, but
equality of taxation and voting by head was omitted. He then dismissed the
assembly, but the members of National Assembly did not move. They said: "We will
not stir from our seats unless forced by bayonets." Following this, many nobles
also joined the commons, and the king eventually gave away and asked others to
follow the suit. The legal, peaceful revolution of the bourgeoisie appeared
victorious at this point. The nobles considered this as a humiliation, albeit
not accepting defeat. The king on the other hand saw the members of National
Assembly as rebels. First step, they had to get rid of the Finance minister who
had supported the National Assembly's cause. He was dismissed arbitrarily and
exiled. The bourgeoisie revolution seemed lost, but they were saved &amp;lt;beat&amp;gt; by
the people, the proletarians, the peasants. That is the third part of the French
Revolution, the Popular revolution!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We hope to talk more about the economic crisis and its effect in a later
episode.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
For the lower classes, the peasants and artisans the crisis plus the recent crop
failure meant hunger and poverty. The hammer-crush burden of the nation's taxes
fell on their thin shoulders. Bread was their staple, and it's prices kept
increasing steadily. The old Finance minister had ordered large purchases from
abroad, and labour camps were setup for distributing food. People, especially in
the countryside were driven into desperation by the active tax collectors. The
masses had to pay taxes, both direct and indirect, and thus pay for their own
oppression. In all these the nobles and monarchy enjoyed their pomp and
luxury. The hungry peasants of France were asked to eat grass by a
governor. There were millions of professional beggars in France then. But the
news of Estates-General kindled hope, a vision of future in them, especially
since it had only happened two centuries ago. They thought, since the king
consulted his people, he pitied their plight, writes Lefebvre. The great hope
also inflamed fearful passions. The Third Estate was convinced that the nobles
would stubbornly defend their privileges. The villagers thought the nobles would
crush them using any measures. Foreign powers would be called to help put down
the villagers. Meanwhile, in the background the dismissal of the good finance
minister was seen as an act of aristocratic conspiracy. So they thought they
should fight, taking up arms, releasing prisoners and recruiting them, forming
their own army against the nobles. The king and the courts thought they should
react to this social hullaballoo to keep things under control. Suddenly the
capital city was filled with 20000 soldiers, much of them were foreign mercenary
troops. That's that!  When a German troop tried to disperse crowd in Paris, the
hungry citizens decided to act, and French guards and military decided to help
the people. They started ransacking the strong points in the city for Guns and
food. Storming into a prison, releasing its inmates, and brutally killing the
guard commander who had earlier ordered to fire on them, the taking of Bastille
was complete. The fall of Bastille.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This quote from William Doyle's French Revolution sums up the episode, "The
National Assembly had seized sovereign power in the name of the France
Nation. It was the founding act of the French Revolution. If the Nation was
sovereign, the king no longer was."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The National Assembly was indirectly helped by the proletarians and the
peasants, and other hungry people of France. One thing to remember is that none
of these happened overnight. For instance, the convocation of the Estates
General was in fact proclaimed in mid 1788, whereas the revolution officially
kicked off a year later in 1789. The economic and political crisis is said to
have begun at least an year earlier before the proclamation of Estates-General
in 1787. It's funny, that Bastille prison only had 7 inmates when it was
stormed.  It rather shows the fall of a symbol of royal power and pride, and the
release of new ideas. The politics of social antagonism which started in Paris
have had now spread to the countryside. The whole feeling later was transcended
into paranoia of loss. We shall stop our narration of the French revolution
here. As they say, the rest is history! That in summary includes:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="org-ol"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abolition of privileges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October Days, when a group of women marched to Versailles to escort the King
to Paris, the epicentre of revolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Church property nationalised&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nobility abolished&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parliament abolished&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civil constitution for Church, i.e. a common platform for Catholics and Protestants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;War with neighbours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liberty Fraternity Equality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monarch executed in 1793&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Massacres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Napoleon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
and much, much more if you wish to zoom in, enough content for another series.
But now we must stop and try to identify links to Political Ideologies.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>podcast</category><category>politics</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/pi_two/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>പയ്യന്റെ മനസ്സിറങ്ങിയോടി</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/payyantemanasiranioodi/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
യാത്രയുടെ തുടക്കത്തിൽ എവിടെയെങ്കിലും ഒന്ന് തേങ്ങയുടയ്ക്കണം എന്ന് തോന്നി. സ്വീകൃത യാദവകുല മുരളീഗാന
വിനോദ മോഹനകര. പഠെ! അവിടെ തന്നെ ഉടച്ചു നാളികേരം. കർപ്പൂരവും കത്തിച്ചു. കുറച്ചുനേരം ഗമധനിസ-യിൽ
വട്ടത്തിരിഞ്ഞു. പിന്നെ നിമ്നോന്നതമായ ആ സ്വരങ്ങളിൽ അങ്ങോട്ടും ഇങ്ങോട്ടും നടന്നു. ഒരു തേങ്ങാപ്പൂളെടുത്ത്
കീശയിലിട്ടു. സന്തോഷായി. നേരെ വിട്ടു വടക്കോട്ട്.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ആര്യവർത്തത്തിന്റെ ചരിത്രത്തെപ്പറ്റി ആലോചിച്ചു. ആരൊക്കയോ വരുണു. എവിടോയെക്കൊയോ പോണു. ഉള്ളതിനെ
പൊളിക്കുന്നു. പുതിയത് പണിയുന്നു. സങ്കൽപ്പത്തിന് ഒറ്റപ്പേര് മതിയെന്ന് വാദിക്കുന്നു. ആ പേരിൽ ചറപറാ
ഹിംസിക്കുന്നു. അതിന്റെ ഇടയിൽ, ഹൈ! മാൽകോൺസ് അല്ലേ ആ കേൾക്കുന്നത്. കുറച്ചുനേരം ഗമധനിസ-യിൽ
വട്ടത്തിരിഞ്ഞു. സംഗീതമെങ്കിലും രക്ഷപെട്ടല്ലോ എന്ന് കരുതി ഗുരുക്കന്മാർക്ക് മനസ്സിൽ മുറുക്കാൻ
മേടിച്ചുകൊടുത്ത് നേരെ തെക്കോട്ട് തീവണ്ടി പിടിച്ചു. ജനലിന്റെ അരികിൽ ഇരുന്നു കാറ്റുകൊണ്ട് ഉറങ്ങി.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ചുറ്റും പല ഉപകരണങ്ങൾ ചിലയ്ക്കുന്നു. മനസ്സിനെ നാല് അശ്വിനികൾ നാലുഭാഗത്തേക്ക് വലിക്കുന്നു. &lt;br&gt;
എന്റെ കൈകാലുകൾ വിടൂ. നിങ്ങൾക്കെന്ത് വേണം പറയൂ.!  &lt;br&gt;
നിന്റെ സമയം. അതാണ് ഞങ്ങൾക്ക് വേണ്ടത്.  &lt;br&gt;
കടവുളേ, കാലനാണല്ലോ കാലം ചോദിച്ച് കാലുപിടിച്ചു വലിക്കുന്നത്. പക്ഷെ എവിടെയോ ഒരു പരിചയം. ഓ,
കാലനല്ല, വിശപ്പാണ്. ചിന്തകൾക്ക് ഭക്ഷണം വേണം. ഉപകരണങ്ങൾ കയ്യിലെടുത്തു. എവിടെയൊക്കെയോ കയറി
വാരി വലിച്ചു തിന്നു. മനസ്സിന്റെ ഭക്ഷണരീതിയിൽ ചിട്ടവരുത്തേണ്ടതിനെ കുറിച്ച് അദൃശ്യവൈദ്യന്മാർ
ആഞ്ഞുപദേശിച്ചതിനെകുറിച്ചോർത്തു. 'ഹെൽത്തി' എന്ന് പേരുള്ള ഒരുതരം ഭക്ഷണം മാത്രമേ
തിന്നാവൂത്രേ. മധുരമത്രെയും ഒഴിവാക്കണം. പക്ഷേ ഈ മനസ്സിന് ഇനിയും ഹെൽത്തിയാവാൻ
സാധിച്ചിട്ടില്ല. ഭഗീരഥേട്ടനെ ഒന്ന് പ്രസംശിച്ചു. രുചിയുള്ള, വറുത്തുപൊരിച്ച, പൊരിച്ചുമൊരിച്ച,
പഞ്ചസാരതൈലത്തിൽ മുക്കിയ ഇത്രയധികം വസ്തുക്കൾ ചുറ്റും മീഡിയകണക്കെ നിറഞ്ഞുനിൽക്കേ, ആർത്തിയെ
ബന്ധിക്കേണ്ടതുണ്ടോ? ചോദ്യം തന്നോടുതന്നെ.  പക്ഷേ, അങ്ങനെ ലോഭങ്ങളെ പൂട്ടിയ ആളുകൾ
പുസ്തകങ്ങളെഴുതുന്നുവെത്രെ. പടി പടിയായുള്ള ഉപദേശങ്ങൾ നിറഞ്ഞ ഒരു മുത്തുച്ചിപ്പി. ഈ പുസ്തകം വായിച്ചാൽ
സ്വയം സഹായിക്കാൻ പറ്റുമെത്രെ. ഭഗീരഥേട്ടനെ വീണ്ടും പ്രസംശിച്ചു. ങ്ഹാ, എന്തായാലും ഈ വരുന്ന
തിങ്കളാഴ്ച്ച തുടങ്ങാം.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ദാ, ഒരു നിശാശലഭം. എവിടെ? പോയോ? പോയി.&lt;br&gt;
അതെന്താ അവിടെ? മലയുടെ മുകളിൽ. &lt;br&gt;
അത് ചന്ദ്രൻ. &lt;br&gt;
അയാൾക്കെന്താ അവിടെ കാര്യം? &lt;br&gt;
നക്ഷത്രങ്ങളെ കൂട്ടി ഭൂമിയോട് യുദ്ധത്തിന് വന്നതാണെത്രെ. &lt;br&gt;
എന്നിട്ടെന്താ ഒന്നും നടക്കാത്തത് ? &lt;br&gt;
ഇപ്പോൾ സീസ്‌ഫയറാണ്  വെടിനിരോധനം. ചർച്ചനടന്നുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുകയാണ്   &lt;br&gt;
സൂര്യനാണ് വിഭീഷണന്റെ റോൾ. &lt;br&gt;
അയാൾ ഈ പണിക്ക് പറ്റുമോ? കടലിൽ പാലമിട്ടാൽ, കടക്കുന്നത് വരെ രാമായണാ, പിന്നെ തേരാപാരായണാന്നാണ്. &lt;br&gt;
ങ്ഹേ? ഞാൻ കേട്ടിട്ടുള്ളത് പാലം കടക്കുന്നത് വരെ രാമാ, കടന്നാൽ നീ പോമാന്നാണ്. &lt;br&gt;
അതെന്തായാലും വേണ്ടില്ല, സംഭവം രാത്രിയായാൽ അയാൾ ചന്ദ്രന്റെ കൂടെയാണ്. &lt;br&gt;
അതൊക്കെ മൂപ്പരുടെ വെറും തരികിടയല്ലേ. ഭൂമിയെയാണയാൾക്കിഷ്ടം. നീ നോക്കിക്കോ, അവസാനം ചന്ദ്രൻ ശശിയാവും, അല്ലെങ്കിൽ സോമൻ, തീർച്ച!  &lt;br&gt;
യുദ്ധം അപ്പൊ തീരൊ ? &lt;br&gt;
ഏഹ്, യുദ്ധം എപ്പോഴും ഉണ്ടാവും. ഇഷ്ടപ്പടിക്ക്! ഇവരെല്ലാവരും കൂടി നമ്മളെയിട്ട് ഇങ്ങനെ കറക്കും അത്രതന്നെ.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ഇഷ്ടപ്പടിക്കോ? ഇതെവിടെയോ കേട്ടിട്ടുണ്ടല്ലോ. ദാ പാലക്കാട്. സുൽത്താൻപേട്ട ജംഗ്ഷൻ എത്തിയപ്പോൾ,
വട്ടവും നോക്കി   വരുംവരായ്കളുടെ ജക്സ്റ്റപൊസിഷൻ എന്താന്നെന്നോർത്ത് അമ്പരന്ന് നിന്ന പയ്യൻ വട്ടം ചുവപ്പിൽ
നിന്നും ആംബർ ആയതറിഞ്ഞില്ല. പോലീസ്‌കാരൻ വാചാലനായി. പിന്നൊന്നും നോക്കിയില്ല. റോങ്ങ്ട്ടേണിൽ നേരെ ഹരിഹരപുത്രക്ക് വിട്ടു. ലക്ഷ്യം മാർഗ്ഗത്തെ സാധൂകരിക്കും എന്ന് പാർത്ഥസാരഥി പറഞ്ഞപ്പോൾ മൂപ്പർക്ക് വിശന്നു കാഞ്ഞിട്ടുണ്ടാവണം. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എന്താ ഏട്ടാ, സൂആംതന്നെ? &lt;br&gt;
ഓ! &lt;br&gt;
ദോശണ്ടാ? &lt;br&gt;
ഇല്ല, റോസ്റ്റേയുളളൂ &lt;br&gt;
വേറെന്താള്ള?  സേവ, വട, ഇലയട, ഇട്ട്ളി, പൊറോട്ട, ചപ്പാത്തി, ഭൂരി &lt;br&gt;
ഭൂരി മതി, 3 എണ്ണം. &lt;br&gt;
കാത്തിരുന്നു. നല്ല ഭുസ്‌ക്ന്നുള്ള മൂന്ന് ഭൂരി വന്നു. ഭൂരി കരുണാകാര എന്ന് സ്വാതിയേട്ടൻ പാടിയതിന്റെ സംഗതി
ഇപ്പൊ പിടികിട്ടി. ഭൂരിയുടെ പെരടികുറ്റിക്ക് നോക്കി ഒരു കുത്തുകുത്തി. കാറ്റ് പൊസ്ക്ക്ന്ന് പോയി. ഹിംസിച്ച
പാപം ഭക്ഷിച്ചാൽ തീരും എന്ന ദാർശനികതയിൽ മസാൽ കൂട്ടി വലിച്ചുവാരി കഴിച്ചു.  ഏട്ടൻ പിന്നേം
വന്നു. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കാപ്പിട്ടോളിൻ. ശക്തൻ. പൻസാര വേണ്ട. &lt;br&gt;
കാപ്പി ആറ്റി ആറ്റി കുടിച്ചു. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&amp;lt;എട്ടനുമായുള്ള ഗീർവാണം ഇവിടെ എഴുതാൻ ഒരു ഓർമപ്പെടുത്തൽ ഭാവിയിലേക്ക് രേഖപ്പെടുത്തി&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കടയിൽനിന്നിറങ്ങി. തത്തക്ക പിത്തക്ക നടന്നു.  ഭയങ്കര സീണം. ഒന്ന് കിടക്കണം.  അടുത്തുള്ള ഒരു വലിയ
അമ്പലത്തിന്റെ കൽത്തിണ്ണയിൽ കിടന്നുറങ്ങി.  ഉള്ളിൽ കയറിയില്ല. അശുദ്ധമാക്കേണ്ടെന്ന് മനസ്സ് സ്വയം
തീരുമാനിച്ചു.  പെട്ടെന്നെണീറ്റു. ഒരു അടുക്കും ചിട്ടയുമില്ല. വേറെവിടെയോ ആണല്ലോ നിന്നിരുന്നത്. ങ്ഹാ,
മലമുകളിൽ, ഭൂമിയും, ചന്ദ്രനും, സൂര്യനും. യുദ്ധം. അല്ലെങ്കിൽ യുദ്ധം വേണ്ട.  എന്നാ കടൽക്കരയിലേക്കു
പോകാം. തീരത്തൂടെ നടക്കാം. ചക്രവാളത്തിന്റെ സ്ട്രക്ച്ചർ കണ്ടാസ്വദിക്കാം. ചാറ്റൽ
മഴയുണ്ടാവും. നന്നായിരിക്കും. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
ങ്ഹേ, ഒറ്റയ്ക്കോ ? മഴയത്ത് പ്രേമിക്കാൻ ആരെങ്കിലും കൂടെ വേണ്ടേ? &lt;br&gt;
അതിനല്ലേ പഴയ കാമുകിമാർ. &lt;br&gt;
കൊണ്ടുവന്നിട്ടുണ്ടോ? &lt;br&gt;
ഓ. എപ്പോഴും കൂടെയുണ്ട്. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
കൈകോർത്ത് നടക്കാം. ഓട്ടപ്പന്തയം വയ്ക്കാം. മുടിയിൽ പിടിച്ചുവലിക്കാം. തോളിൽ കയ്യിട്ടു ചെവിയിൽ
ഉഫ്ന്നു കാറ്റൂതാം. അങ്ങനെയൊക്കെ സ്നേഹം പ്രകടിപ്പിക്കാം. പിന്നെ കവിത ചൊല്ലി
ബുദ്ധിമുട്ടിക്കാം. അയ്യോ, കവിത മുട്ടുന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
എഴുതാൻ വാഞ്ഛ! &lt;br&gt;
പക്ഷേ, എന്റെ പേനക്ക് നീരിളക്കം വരുന്നില്ല. &lt;br&gt;
നളിനി, നളിനകാന്തി, മായാമോഹിനി &lt;br&gt;
മലയാളപദങ്ങളെ, &lt;br&gt;
നിങ്ങളെ മോചിപ്പിക്കാൻ, &lt;br&gt;
എന്നെ ആശ്വസിപ്പിക്കാൻ, &lt;br&gt;
എനിക്കാശ്രയിക്കാൻ,&lt;br&gt;
ആശയങ്ങളെവിടെ? &lt;br&gt;
അശ്വാരൂഢസാഹിത്യയോദ്ധാക്കളെ,&lt;br&gt;
ഗുരുക്കന്മാരെ, &lt;br&gt;
അതികായരെ, എന്റെ അതിഥികളെ, &lt;br&gt;
സരസസരസനായ ഈ പയ്യനെ സഹായിക്കൂ,&lt;br&gt;
അനുഗ്രഹിക്കൂ,&lt;br&gt;
എനിക്കെഴുതാൻ വാഞ്ഛ.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
ഹാവൂ, ഒരു സുഖമുണ്ടിപ്പോൾ. ഇനി തിരിച്ചു പോകാം. ശിരോസ്‌ഥിക്കുള്ളിൽ വിശ്രമിക്കാം.  വന്ന വഴി
തിരിച്ചുനടന്നപ്പോൾ കുറച്ചു തേങ്ങാപ്പൂളുക്കൾ ചിതറി കിടക്കുന്നതു കണ്ടു. ഒന്നെടുത്തപ്പോൾ അതിലെന്തോ
വരപ്പെടുത്തിയിരിക്കുന്നു. 'ഗ'. തൊട്ടടുത്തതിൽ 'മ'. പിന്നെ അടുത്തതിൽ 'ധ', പിന്നെ 'നി'. എല്ലാം
ചേർത്തി വച്ച് വായിച്ചു. എന്തോ ഒരു കുറവ് സ്പഷ്ടം. ചുറ്റും പരതി, ആകാശത്തേക്ക് നോക്കി,
ങ്ഹേ.. കിട്ടിയില്ല. പെട്ടെന്ന് ഉള്ളിലേക്ക് നോക്കി. സ്വന്തം പോക്കറ്റിന്റെയുള്ളിൽ. 'സ' കിട്ടി. അതിനെ
പൊട്ടിച്ചു. ചെറിയ കഷണം ഇടതുഭാഗത്തും വലുത് വലത്തും വച്ചു. എന്നിട്ടു ചേർത്ത് തിരിച്ചും മറിച്ചും
പാടിക്കൊണ്ട് നടന്നു.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
സ ഗ മ ധ നി സ &lt;br&gt;
സ നി ധ മ ഗ സുഭം. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>comedy</category><category>payyan</category><category>satire</category><category>പയ്യൻ</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/payyantemanasiranioodi/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 21:25:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Political Ideologies - The beginning</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/pi_one/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
"Listen – strange women lying in ponds distributing swords is no basis for a
system of government. Supreme executive power derives from a mandate from the
masses, not from some farcical aquatic ceremony."
says Michael Palin's character in the film Monty Python and the Holy Grail.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Well, in today's episode we begin the series of discourse about supreme power
and masses and governments.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Political ideologies.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It's rather a difficult topic to discuss, isn't it? Where to begin, what to say,
what not to utter, all those epoch defining events, everlasting personalities,
textbook terminologies, its immortal influence in the past, present, and dare I
say, the future! And such is the fatality of this topic that our original plan
to discuss it under "Dumb it down to me" series, was deemed dumb
unanimously. Like a live fish, the harder you try to grasp it, the farther it
escapes. At any rate, an optimistic attempt is vital, so, Welcome, to Hitchens'
Razor!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Liberalism, Conservatism, Left, Right, Fascism, Socialism, Communism,
Libertarianism, Nationalism, Left of centre, Right of centre, uff, and yet, here
we are; One has to wonder, how has these managed to remain relevant to the
modern world?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Now, our attempt to be pragmatic in this episode, say, to rather talk about the
juicy events of the past, than to be tediously academic, wouldn't mean that this
episode would be any less boring than your current imagination. In fact, such a
statement would be euphemistic to a fool's errand around a Mobius band. Such is
the fatality of this topic. If you are not bored already,
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Let's begin, by travelling back to a time when the word Ideology did not exist.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orga7ac84b" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orga7ac84b"&gt;Recap of history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orga7ac84b"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If we are to believe in contemporary consensus, then "Life began in the
ocean". Some creatures subsequently crawled up to the landmass; the
reptiles. They had sex, laid eggs, and abandoned them, moved on to next honey
moon. Reptile nonchalance is criminally underrated.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then came the birds. They developed wings and feathers to counter the cold. They
had intercourse and more eggs were delivered. But unlike the reptiles, they
started caring about their eggs; by keeping them warm under their wings and
fuselage. The first act of true selfishness.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Enter mammals, with the hitherto unknown notion of storing eggs inside its own
body, inside its own body!. Such was the shock, bird brains accomplished maximum
cognisance, and reptiles simply looked up. Mammals also acquired the habit of
providing protection and nutrition to the offspring. This created attachment
between the youngling and the parent, and it kindled the possibility of learning
by imitation. The beginnings of a true social life. As H.G.Wells put it, "A
teachable type of life had come into the world". And thus we evolved!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Well, the point is, we evolved as a species from Reptiles and Birds to Mammals,
to Hunter Gatherers; we had the early civilizations in Egypt, India, Mesopotamia
and China. We had Aryans and Dravidians, the panchayat or the village system,
the great thinkers Kong Fu-Tse(Confucious), Lao-Tse and Buddha. We had the
kingdom of Persia, the great Greek period, conquests of Alexander, the Mauryan
dynasty, Kautilya and Arthashastra, Hellenistic Greece, Ashoka, Rome, Carthage,
Caesar, Pompey, Augustus, Cleopatra, Jesus of Nazareth, Constantinople, Holy
Roman Church, the Orthodox church, Goths, Huns, Vandals, Islam, Xuanzang(Hsuen
Tsang), Charlesmagne, The fall of Rome, Chalukyas, Pallavas, Rashtrakutas,
Pandyas, Cholas, Ghazni, Genghis Khan, Marco Polo, Timur, Dark Ages, Crusades,
the Renaissance, Age of Science, Age of Enlightenment, Age of Revolution,
and then the FRENCH REVOLUTION happened.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
1789
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The word ideology was coined, literally a new ‘science of ideas’.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Thence we had Marx, Nietzsche, Electricity, Russian Revolution- part 1, WW- part
1, Russian Revolution - part 2, the Great Depression, WW-part 2, Electronics,
Computers, Cold War, Globalization, Internet, Climate change, Covid and now,
now, as in, the now, now-now, at the moment now.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Now, hopefully that painted a vague timeline of our history. Now, we slip on a
banana peel and fall into the coming of ideologies.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgd6b0f4d" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="orgd6b0f4d"&gt;The coming of Ideologies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-orgd6b0f4d"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It is in Europe where the seeds of modern political ideologies germinated at a
time when politics revolved around religion and religion only. The idea of
nationality which is obvious these days was rather a niche topic then. War was
the most dangerous pandemic in the continent, and religion was the most
important cog in the war machine. Christians, other Christians, Muslims, other
Muslims endlessly fought and killed to protect their version of the
supernatural.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org1ee90ce" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org1ee90ce"&gt;Feudal System and the Middle class&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org1ee90ce"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Violence and disorder prevailed both internally and externally. Strong people
seized land and power, and they built strong castles for own protection, as they
were always under threat from people like themselves. The peasants were not
organized and couldn't defend themselves, so they sold their allegiance to these
lords in castles. The small lords served the bigger lords, and the big lords
bowed to the monarch. The Feudal System!. The Church, and its officials were
also part of this. The idea of equality or of freedom was exempted in this
system.  Thus the middle ages passed under feudal system where peasants lived
miserably. There were occasional revolts from the peasants, but they were
cruelly put down by the upper classes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org533a1eb" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="org533a1eb"&gt;The bourgeoisie&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-org533a1eb"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There was also another type of people, a floating class including the traders
and merchants. They were not part of the feudal system per se, but they had no
wealth or influence in that society. But the discovery of sea routes radically
changed the fortunes of these daring people. Sea routes opened markets far east
and west of Europe. Asia, America and other parts of the world became accessible
to them.  The middle-class, aka the bourgeoisie thus gathered wealth from global
trade, and the new money fetched them privileges, and eventually power. They
still had two classes above them, the nobles and the clergy, and of course the
king at the top. This segregation based on class is officially called the
&lt;i&gt;Ancien Regime&lt;/i&gt;, which had policies and taxation controlling the freedom of the
tradesmen. Naturally this was increasingly becoming a hindrance to the
bourgeoisie, as they disliked the fact that the classes above them got money
without work, and representation without taxation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgf06225a" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="orgf06225a"&gt;Three 'R's&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-orgf06225a"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And then there were the three great movements of the era: Renaissance,
Reformation, and Revolution. The renaissance was about learning, science,
experimental rationalism and asking questions about the universe. Hopefully,
more of Renaissance in another series. Now, Reformation was about religion,
specifically Christianity, and of Revolutions, there were three.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org651d2b1" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org651d2b1"&gt;Reformation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org651d2b1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We shall start with the Reformation.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Printing! The Arabs learned paper-making form the Chinese, and Europe learnt it
from the Arabs. Towards the end of 15th century, paper and printing became
common. This meant common people could read books themselves, didn't need a
priest to tell them the content of the Bible.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Rome was the epicentre of European Christianity in this era. At some point the
Roman Church thought heresy hunting would be a fabulous idea. Apparently, there
was fun to be derived and lessons to be taught by burning people alive at stakes
if they questioned the ways of the church. Women were branded as witches and
burnt alive publicly. The infamous Spanish Inquisition formed during this time,
epitomised this sport by underlining the word hunting in heresy hunting. Many
more heinous crimes of unspeakable nature were committed in this time by the
self appointed guardians of god and faith. Early in the 16th century, Martin
Luther, a Christian priest visited Rome, and he was disgusted by its corruption
and luxury. He was a leader who protested against the Holy Roman Church, and
thus formed the christian faction Protestants, against the Roman Catholic,
RC. This Protestant movement gathered pace when young princes and nobles sided
with the protestants to put an end to all attempts made by the Pope to dominate
over them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In England, Henry VIII, favoured the protestants because he wanted to divorce
his wife and marry another woman, which the Roman Catholic Church, naturally,
was against. So he formed another church called the Church of England, and
established himself as the Head of the Church, and married the woman. He was
then the head of the state and head of the church. Well, why not? god is
omnipresent isn't it?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Italy, France, Austria, and Spain were Catholic at the time. Germany was half
protestant.  The middle class carried the Protestantism with them; wherever they
were strong, protestants thrived. But reformation was not enough to bring down
the kings, they were still powerful and autocratic as ever. The monarch
remained, and waited for the revolutions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgfdc2c7e" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orgfdc2c7e"&gt;Netherlands, Switzerland and England&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-orgfdc2c7e"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before we get to the three big revolutions it is worth mentioning Netherlands,
Switzerland and England. Netherlands became republic even before the French
Revolution. There was a heroic but bloody battle that happened between the
merchant classes bourgeoisie of Holland and King Philip II of Spain, who at that
time ruled the region. Switzerland also gained independence around this time
from the Holy Roman Empire after the Thirty Years war.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
England, had the parliament in place with two houses, mostly represented by the
lords and nobles at the upper house, and the merchants and wealthy middle class
in the lower house. The parliament eventually became stronger than the monarch,
at a point where its King was beheaded at the orders of the parliament, only to
be later replaced with a puppet from elsewhere in Europe, Germany I
think. England is a curious case, where the Gentlemen and the Bourgeoisie joined
to share power with the king.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orge3c7b5d" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="orge3c7b5d"&gt;The Three Revolutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-orge3c7b5d"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It is interesting that three revolutions happened broadly around the same time
in history. The political revolution in North America, the industrial revolution
in England, and the social revolution in France.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-orgbc21162" class="outline-4"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="orgbc21162"&gt;American Revolution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-4" id="text-orgbc21162"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
War is so demanding, it exhausts the resources of a kingdom, which in turn
demands from its masses, more suffering that is.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
For the British Government, the umpteenth war with France meant need for more
money, and they decide to squeeze the colonies to breakeven. The American
colonies resisted, and when the British East India Company tried to force the
colony to buy their tea, the colonists boycotted the act, and some colonists
threw the tea overboard from the ships. Cut to war scenes where France helped
the American Colonists. Cut to British accepting defeat. Cut to the signing of
the Declaration of Independence, with the famous cry, No taxation without
representation. The declaration also said, "All men are born equal" &amp;lt;beat/pause&amp;gt;
except the negroes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
and, in the next episode, The French Revolution.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>podcast</category><category>politics</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/pi_one/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>