<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VINODH's NOTES (Posts about English)</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://vinotes.github.io/categories/cat_english.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:vinotes@gmail.com"&gt;Vinodh MJ Human&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 20:38:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Yellow Balloon</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/yellow-balloon/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The night, soothingly quiet, Poet awoke in her bed,&lt;br&gt;
A story emerged, an idea raged inside her head.&lt;br&gt;
She leapt to her desk, and started scribbling away,&lt;br&gt;
In hope that the memory of her dream would stay.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Lying on a hammock she thought-thought,&lt;br&gt;
About last night’s dream that she caught.&lt;br&gt;
A story that she wanted to tell-tell,&lt;br&gt;
But out of her mind it suddenly fell.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Something about a familiar young girl,&lt;br&gt;
Who wore a necklace made of pearl.&lt;br&gt;
Ah..! the curious world inside a crystal bowl,&lt;br&gt;
And indeed a villain to make the story whole!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Enter the villain, with a yellow balloon in his hand,&lt;br&gt;
Seven feet tall, skinny lad was all tanned.&lt;br&gt;
With him he brought his own music band,&lt;br&gt;
That played popular songs which were banned.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Yellow balloon hovered above his head like a halo,&lt;br&gt;
Her eyes twinkled as she went to say hello.&lt;br&gt;
Will you give me that yellow balloon that I crave?&lt;br&gt;
Quid pro quo the pearl necklace, I will take it to my grave.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I will not give you the necklace.&lt;br&gt;
Is that so young lady? why? may I ask?&lt;br&gt;
Because you’re the villain in this story,&lt;br&gt;
Yes! but villains are also part of history.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Don't villains invariably lose in the end?&lt;br&gt;
Right you are! here is your yellow balloon, my friend.&lt;br&gt;
She reached out for the balloon, and he let it fly,&lt;br&gt;
Hahahaa! where's the fun in not letting it touch the sky.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
She woke up with a start, still lying on her hammock,&lt;br&gt;
The pearl necklace planted safely on her neck.&lt;br&gt;
She slid into her chair, and started scribbling away,&lt;br&gt;
In hope that the memory of her dream would stay.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The night, soothingly quiet, is coming to its end,&lt;br&gt;
As Poet looked outside the balcony, facing the wind.&lt;br&gt;
Words rhyming on her book; Pearl necklace on her neck,&lt;br&gt;
She smiled at an yellow balloon dawning up in the sky.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/yellow-balloon/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>City Rain</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/cityrain/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Like an ancient civilization, the city slept,&lt;br&gt;
In an endless commute, its way of life wept.&lt;br&gt;
In mirky buildings and sulky streets,&lt;br&gt;
Boredom grumbled, and happiness crumbled.&lt;br&gt;
Hither and yon, people ran to make ends meet,&lt;br&gt;
And that's when, the first drop of rain came to greet.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
His highness's arrival was announced by Dhol drums,&lt;br&gt;
Boisterously, it lifted the city out of its doldrums.&lt;br&gt;
Bewitched the wind, into a wicked poltergeist,&lt;br&gt;
Possessed the trees like an unseen ghost,&lt;br&gt;
Made them dance with no rhyme, nor reason,&lt;br&gt;
The city was under its spell, in a dry summer season.&lt;br&gt;
Windows were shattered; for wind owes nothing in the end.&lt;br&gt;
Clothes were brandished; so one shall never pretend.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, across the tar road, he boarded a bus, red,&lt;br&gt;
Sitting by a window, he peered outside - pandemonium appeared.&lt;br&gt;
Citizens with books, and bags, and sarees above their head,&lt;br&gt;
Steam rising, from a packed tea shop in the distance, up ahead,&lt;br&gt;
A woman was wrestling with wind; to ignite a cigarette,&lt;br&gt;
Strolling while nature is mopping; a singular etiquette.&lt;br&gt;
A buoyant umbrella was floating in a whirlwind,&lt;br&gt;
Nature, thus mocking the anticipation of humankind.&lt;br&gt;
The rain gained momentum as the bus coughed forward,&lt;br&gt;
He looked behind and saw memories travelleing backward.&lt;br&gt;
Closed his eyes, the downpour deluged his face with euphoria,&lt;br&gt;
A song surfaced from his childhood that rhymed with liquid nostalgia.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, she picked up the book, her precious company,&lt;br&gt;
The wooden arm chair, beckoned her from the spacious balcony;&lt;br&gt;
Feet up on the chair, rocking back and forth,&lt;br&gt;
She witnessed sky coalesce with earth.&lt;br&gt;
Closed her eyes; her breath flooded heart with petrichor,&lt;br&gt;
Opened the book; her brain vessels capsized in bibliochor.&lt;br&gt;
For once, her heart and brain agreed to this moment,&lt;br&gt;
That purpose of life is - Knowledge - makes one content.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, they said, let's keep playing,&lt;br&gt;
This can't get any better, keep the ball rolling.&lt;br&gt;
The rain couldn't drench their jerseys wet,&lt;br&gt;
For they were already saturated in sweat.&lt;br&gt;
Raindrops crossing flood lights was quite a sight,&lt;br&gt;
Win this special game, they must, with all their might.&lt;br&gt;
Awaits, a hot water bath, a biryani, and perhaps a drive into the night,&lt;br&gt;
When the city shines bright, and the night grows young until the first light.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, he sought her presence,&lt;br&gt;
She was not found in their residence.&lt;br&gt;
He looked at the flight of stairs,&lt;br&gt;
Spun on his feet, and went up to the terrace.&lt;br&gt;
There she stood staring at the sky,&lt;br&gt;
Palms open, her hands were lifted shoulder high.&lt;br&gt;
Her pink clothes soaked from head-to-toe,&lt;br&gt;
He moved closer and hugged her apropos.&lt;br&gt;
She stepped on his feet; He kissed on top of her head,&lt;br&gt;
With hands wrapped around his chest, her face rested.&lt;br&gt;
In that chilling juxtaposition, they stood in silence,&lt;br&gt;
Under the rain, they melded into the timeless ambience.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, Poet moved to the kitchen,&lt;br&gt;
For a cup of tea with a hint of mint and lemon.&lt;br&gt;
The curtains swung over the room irking the shadows,&lt;br&gt;
A venerable fountain pen lay on the table in its repose.&lt;br&gt;
The pen kissed the paper, then and back again,&lt;br&gt;
Until Poet read the words, "City Rain".&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/cityrain/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 15:59:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>No reply</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/noreply/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;div id="outline-container-org5e38dfa" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org5e38dfa"&gt;Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org5e38dfa"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Day 1 : No reply.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Day 2 : No reply.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Well, what's the point of being in a messaging ecosystem if we don't yield to
its temptations? To keep the civilization going, one must engage in learned
discourse, vociferous debates and rude emoticon exchanges. Simply put, one must
reply to a friend's message.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Think about it this way:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Millenial Ramayanam. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lakshmana"&gt;Lakshmanan&lt;/a&gt; on his death bed. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rama"&gt;Raman&lt;/a&gt; pings &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanuman"&gt;Hanuman&lt;/a&gt;, "&lt;i&gt;Bro,
ngl, Lak is fried… bad scene… URGENT!… need Sanjeevani ASAP!!!&lt;/i&gt;" Assume a
scenario where Hanuman ignores the text, and Gen-Y Raman is adamant not to make
a phone call to assert the gravity of the situation. It simply ain't cool to
call. Couple of days later Hanuman reaches the base camp, smoking chillum, lit
af, and through the chillum smoke he sees another huge smoke screen in front of
him; understands it is coming from Lakshmanan's funeral pyre, and cries WTAF !!!
Now, Raman has one less thing to worry about, and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sugriva"&gt;Sugreevan&lt;/a&gt; is still plucking
Tulsi leaves one at a time in a Himalayan valley thinking it must be &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sanjeevani_(plant)"&gt;Sanjeevani&lt;/a&gt;,
going by its smell. What a fate!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Well, luckily, Hanuman, my hero, your hero, our hero, everyone's hero, replied
immediately "BRB", took the next flight and brought the entire freaking
mountain. The episode ended with a close-up shot of Lakshmanan eating protein
bars and Greek salad on his path to full fitness and Sugreevan is smoking
chillum in the background. Shubham!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My dear friends, moral of the story is that one must reply to their friend's
messages at the earliest.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Jai Hanuman. Many peace.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org4aa37e2" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org4aa37e2"&gt;Terminology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org4aa37e2"&gt;
&lt;table border="2" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="6" rules="groups" frame="hsides"&gt;


&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col class="org-left"&gt;

&lt;col class="org-left"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th scope="col" class="org-left"&gt;Usage&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th scope="col" class="org-left"&gt;Closest meaning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;Bro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;Short for brother also known as Bruh a.k.a Bruv.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;ngl&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;not gonna lie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;gonna&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;going to&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;Lak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;short for Lakshmanan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;scene&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;plight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;fried&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;in trouble&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;ASAP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;as soon as possible&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;lit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;intoxicated or under the influence of some substance; exciting, outstanding, or amazing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;af&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;as f word&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;f&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;another usage of fornication commonly spelled a f@*k&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;ain't&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;no f-ing idea what that means&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;WTAF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;what the actual F word&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;BRB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class="org-left"&gt;be right back&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>satire</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/noreply/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 01:15:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>You Will Never Walk Alone!</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/ynwa/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
For a lifelong Liverpool F.C fan, this is the perfect gift.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I found a poem inside it. My friend Harish, a proud Chelsea F.C fan wrote this&lt;br&gt;
poem. He understands football better than anyone else. Football is mostly&lt;br&gt;
happiness, sometimes sorrow, triumphs and heartbreaks. It is freedom. It is a&lt;br&gt;
religion without animosity. We all love the game and the game loves us&lt;br&gt;
back. Football is love!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://vinotes.github.io/galleries/stevie.jpg" alt="nil"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Do you remember? Is it a blur? Reminisce,&lt;br&gt;
As you sailed through the highs and the lows,&lt;br&gt;
Through the soaring peaks and the infinte abyss,&lt;br&gt;
Darkness, the roll of a dice, chaos, the fall of a domino.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The words of a special anthem echoes&lt;br&gt;
Softly, just like it did in Turkey and Madrid&lt;br&gt;
A wave of red, devoured the green meadows&lt;br&gt;
Millions of souls dreamt, breathless, achieve it they did!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That echo is now a roar, your ears hurt&lt;br&gt;
Do not resist, for it is a beacon of hope&lt;br&gt;
Pull up your socks, be ready and be alert&lt;br&gt;
For even in the face of defeat, you will kop(e)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The walk is now a jog, the road to salvation&lt;br&gt;
The time to show how much you've grown&lt;br&gt;
A fallen tear, broken heart, a whisper, a realisation&lt;br&gt;
For even in lucid dreams, you'll never walk alone.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
by &lt;i&gt;Harish Ramachandran&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
YNWA!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>football</category><category>poem</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/ynwa/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:50:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mammae</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/mammae/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Reading time : 5 minutes&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Let us travel back to the age of reptiles. Early reptiles understood the need
for world sustainability by reproduction, hence they happily mated, laid eggs
and moved on to next honey moon. Reptile nonchalance is criminally underrated.
They left their eggs to sun and season to hatch. A reptile life thus begins and
ends with its own experiences. Bliss!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Enter the birds. They developed feathers and wings to counter the cold.  They
had intercourse and more eggs were delivered. Then they broke the age old
reptile tradition, and started caring about their eggs by keeping them warm and
guarding them from danger. The first act of true selfishness in the evolution of
Evolution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Mammals! When birds thought hair instead of feathers was perfectly stupid,
mammals came up with the hitherto unknown notion of having sex and storing eggs
inside its own body. Inside the body!!! Such was the shock, bird brains attained
its maximum cognisance and reptiles retired from being related. The mammalian
eggs came out alive from their body and started crying for food. The mountains
and tadpoles echoed the melancholy. Mammals, then acquired the habit of
providing protection and nutrition to the offspring. Thus began the suckling and
tickling. This Mammalian care lead to mutual understanding and association
between the parent and the offspring. The cherishing of the youngling created
attachment, and kindled the possibility of learning by imitation. The beginnings
of true social life.  As H.G.Wells has rightly said, "A &lt;i&gt;teachable&lt;/i&gt; type of life
had come into the world". The student then became the teacher, thoughts replaced
lessons, and life advanced in the world. Here we are!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Secreting or not, all mammalian genders have mammary glands. One gender ceasing
to mature at an early age and another maturing at a later stage.  Unravelling
this bias, a primitive hypothesis suggested that the early mammal children were
truly sexist, and chose to suck nipple(s) of one specific gender while
disdainfully ignoring the other. The continuous process of suckling and sucking
might have caused the growth in the former, and the categorical humiliation
could have hindered the growth in the latter. The fallacious theory dared to
compare Mammae to the ever expanding universe.  Regardless of the intellectual
snobbery, it opened up a new space of body research, which, the Children Of
Science(COS a.k.a Cause) informally called as 'The shape of you'.  Apart from
this, two questions of great fiscal and monetary importance are: "Since when did
one start wearing the inevitable as an embellishment to poverty, and the other
consider this evolutionary augmentation as a world wonder"?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The United League Of Nations(TULON), is seriously contemplating re-introduction
of &lt;i&gt;'Mulakkaram'&lt;/i&gt;, loosely translated to Breast Tax, which, till the early 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;
century, was the tax imposed on lower caste women if they wanted to cover their
breasts in public. The women were expected to pay the government a tax on their
bosom, as soon as they started developing them. The tax collectors would visit
every house to collect Breast(Either of the two fleshy milk-secreting glandular
organs on the chest of a woman) tax from any lower caste women who passed the
age of puberty. The tax was evaluated by the collectors depending on the size of
their breasts. An American newspaper casually called it as "The Cover Charge",
and people laughed for seven consecutive days. Later, they were all hanged,
drawn and quartered for the simple crime of shamelessness. The current
generation of people in this geographical area unanimously agreed that they are
ashamed of their ancestry.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The famous English thought on "To cover or not to cover" continues to baffle the
intelligent society. An armchair thinker once said: "A man went outside a bar
and looked behind to find it sacrilegious; but from the inside he found it
perfectly ordinary". In some parts of the world, people are happy not covering
their body or smile, whereas in some other parts of the world covering head to
toe is the stepping stone to nirvana. Rest of the world believes in heuristic
principles.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
To abruptly end is merciful.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Many peace.
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Kindly leave your feedback &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mind_toilet/status/1308355288609685505?s=20"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>history</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/mammae/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 19:05:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Resonating thoughts</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/matching-thoughts/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I recently read an &lt;a href="https://aeon.co/ideas/hypocognition-is-a-censorship-tool-that-mutes-what-we-can-feel"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about hypocognition. It is the state where a feeling,
a concept, or a phenomenon cannot be put into words.  For example, what's the
word for &lt;i&gt;the vague uncomfortable feeling of sitting on a seat that is still
radiating warmth from someone else’s bottom&lt;/i&gt;? It is called &lt;i&gt;Shoeburyness&lt;/i&gt;. I had
such an experience, not shoeburyness, that I have had in many a wonderful
occasions. Hypocognition happened.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I think, therefore I am sometimes able to enjoy certain moments of exquisite
intellectual pleasure of becoming aware that a completely unrelated person in
the world, dead or alive, has resonated with my thoughts. Once in a bed I
thought: "There are certain things in the world which will not bend to
force. Things that cannot be acquired by power, but are presented by faith and
happiness. &lt;b&gt;Love!&lt;/b&gt; I strongly believe that love is for those who deserve it. The
wealthiest human cannot find an ounce of love any of the shops in the world. The
strongest human can never feel love through arm wrestling. Love cannot be
snatched, bought or bartered. That's where the satisfaction of giving takes
birth.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Books are wonderful objects. My friend might think me queer to call it an
object. People think books have feelings. So do I. Currently, I am reading
Siddhartha by Herman Hesse. Today, I read this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Siddhartha&lt;/b&gt; : "Oh, he's strong, the Samana, and he isn't afraid of anything. He
could force you, beautiful girl. He could kidnap you. He could hurt you."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Kamala&lt;/b&gt; : "No, Samana, I am not afraid of this. Did any Samana or Brahman ever
fear, someone might come and grab him and steal his learning, and his religious
devotion, and his depth of thought? No, for they are his very own, and he would
only give away from those whatever he is willing to give and to whomever he is
willing to give. Like this it is, precisely like this it is also with Kamala and
with pleasures o love. Beautiful and red is Kamala's mouth, but just try to kiss
it against Kamala's will, and you will not obtain a single drop of sweetness
from it, which knows how to give so many sweet things! You are learning easily,
Siddhartha, thus you should also learn this: love can be obtained by begging,
buying, receiving it as a gift, finding it in the street, but it cannot be
stolen. In this, you have come up with the wrong path. No, it would be a pity,
if a pretty young man like you would want to tackle it in such a wrong manner."
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What do we call it? Herman Hesse and I thinking about same topic? I don't have a
word for it, so I am going with…
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Resonating thoughts!
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Kindly leave your feedback &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mind_toilet/status/1308353846456889344?s=20"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>serious</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/matching-thoughts/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:06:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Make us dream!</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/a-football-dream/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Liverpool FC is my football club. Palakkad is my beautiful home town in Kerala, India.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I had a dream.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Liverpool FC came to Palakkad to play a football game. Sadio Mane started the
game on bench, but he chose to stand with the fans. A confident young boy was
standing next to him in the stadium.  Naturally, they became friends.
Unforeseen, as is usually the case with nature, the game was cancelled few
minutes into it.  I asked Sadio, “Will you play football with us in my school?“
He said yes. So I took him to Navodaya Vidyalaya, Palakkad, the best school in
the world. I introduced Sadio to my friends and they all were ready for a game.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://vinotes.github.io/galleries/NavodayaGround.JPG" alt="nil"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sadio fell in love with the ground the moment he saw it. Western ghats in the
backdrop and the amazing Palakkadan wind made him whisper: “This is where I want
to play day in day out”. Sadio played in my team's attack and I played in the
midfield. When my goalkeeper played a simple ball to me, I looked up the field
and saw Sadio making the run. With my barefoot, I sliced the ball and it was
airborne. Seconds later, that touch by Sadio, and the finish, the ball was in
the back of the net. The trend continued, he made those runs, and I sent him
through on the goal.  We won!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
After the post match handshake and hug, Sadio asked me: “Why don’t you come to
Melwood some day?”  in French obviously. I smiled, and said “Oui, I will
try. Merci beaucoup”.  Sadio flew back to England.  On the plane, he spoke to a
man called Jurgen Klopp and a week later, I got a call from Liverpool FC, the
best football club in the world.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I landed in John Lennon airport. Imagine all the people, waiting for my arrival.
I reached Melwood, Liverpool FC's training ground.  Sadio introduced me to his
friends. Virgil was taller than me.  Trent is younger than me. Robbo warned me
about Millie's humour sense.  Mo's English was better than mine. I gave Ali a
chocolate and he kept it. I told Bobby he is my favourite player. The boss gave
me hug and said welcome. I was home.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I wore boots for evening's training session. Sadio told the boss that he wanted
me to play in his side. I scored one, assisted twice, made a goal saving tackle
and broke my ankle.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Hendo lifted the ball onto Mo's path, who cut it back to Bobby, who nonchalantly
flicked it into the space behind Virgil.  I was too quick for the big man. Blink
of an eye, I slotted the ball past Adrian and copied a Bobby celebration.  Then
Allison played a simple ball to me, I looked up the field and saw Sadio making
the run.  I sliced the ball and it was airborne.  Seconds later, that touch by
Sadio and the finish, the ball was in the back of the net. The second assist
followed a neat link up play between Bobby, Mo, Sadio and Me.  Bobby's no look
finish met my cross at the far post. Jurgen's celebration to that was wild.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I might have kicked the wall too hard. That's how I woke up with a broken ankle,
but it was definitely worth the dream. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
YNWA!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Kindly leave your feedback &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mind_toilet/status/1308352777194598400?s=20"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>fantasy</category><category>football</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/a-football-dream/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 21:15:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mighty Mountains</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/mighty-mountains/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://vinotes.github.io/galleries/dhanteras.JPG" alt="nil"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Mighty mountains, I saw its curves and peaks,&lt;br&gt;
Up above and far away, amongst clouds and skies.&lt;br&gt;
Through pathless woods, I shall climb to the top,&lt;br&gt;
A strange voice inside my head, but I did not stop.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
First came the rain, making my feet wet,&lt;br&gt;
Then came the sun, making my brow sweat.&lt;br&gt;
Pain building in body, but I couldn't care less,&lt;br&gt;
Then I crossed a line, that made the trees jealous&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Slippery stones, my mind must decide quick,&lt;br&gt;
The next crucial step in this trek.&lt;br&gt;
For the wrong choice could be as fatal,&lt;br&gt;
As a life, with no adventure to tell.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Alas, I saw the yellow tent by the riverside,&lt;br&gt;
In a valley like a silver necklace on a bride.&lt;br&gt;
Stretched my shape, and washed my face,&lt;br&gt;
With water so cold, that set my wits ablaze.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Twilight flirted with day and night,&lt;br&gt;
Sky blushed as it turned orange, bright.&lt;br&gt;
Adios, I am done for the day, said the setting Sun.&lt;br&gt;
'See you on the other side' was Earth's cunning pun.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The river carried mountain's letter to the sea.&lt;br&gt;
The poem rhymed words of passionate love to me.&lt;br&gt;
Fate, they cannot unite; divided by an invisible wall.&lt;br&gt;
Faith! the mountain awaited the next rainfall.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I looked up, now the canvas was painted black,&lt;br&gt;
A full moon and a thousand splendid suns smiled back.&lt;br&gt;
I walked for long, forlorn, with a mind full of peace.&lt;br&gt;
Mighty mountains, I loved its curves and peaks.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Kindly leave your feedback &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mind_toilet/status/1308347802901118977?s=20"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/mighty-mountains/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 20:27:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Crime scene</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/crime-scene/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;What happened?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I was reading a book and suddenly heard a loud noise from outside.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Can you please elaborate?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That's what sir, BANG!, and seconds later, a second BANG.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Will you be able to recreate your evening till the incident?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Yes, sir. Yesterday I came back late from work to attend two more late evening
meetings. Ms. Elusive Luck's birthday, both meetings got cancelled at my
arrival. So, I practised music for what I thought was an hour.  Sir, It was a
good workout, and by the end I was sweating and shivering from forehead to
heels. I wrapped the set, and was hungrily wandering indoors.  That's when i saw
the most beautiful thing on my study table. A banana!  Who keeps a banana on a
study table, sir? Well, I did. Yesterday morning.  Sync sir, Unbelievable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Alright, then what?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sir, I thought of cooking dinner. Dosa in my mind, I found couple of duck eggs
in the fridge. 'Egg Dosa' creeped, sorry, crept into my head. I fetched Dosa
batter and eggs to the warmth outside. Roasted some curry leaves, and ground
them with chillies into a lush green paste. Fried some Coin Pappads as well.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
An eerie silence lurked in the kitchen while I was chopping onions. I added salt
and a pinch of turmeric to the onions. Then I introduced our dear eggs to Madame
la Guillotine, CRACK! its viscous yellow head crashed into the bowl.  I stirred
a motley mixture with all that. When the pan on the stove started whispering to
the winds I threw a water blanket over it. The pan hissed and shot
sodium-in-water tantrums at me. I calmly slid the hot bubbling bubbles into the
sink. Then I painted a solar system on the pan with batter.  The system had to
be perfect. A subtle press in the center followed by concentric Sufi
whirling. It must spread into a round Gaussian distribution and scatter a
Brownian motion of batter pores. The pores would channel the steam upwards,
cooking the layers above en route its itinerary. Then, I sprayed oil, and
smeared the lush green paste on top of the maturing Dosa.  Few seconds later, I
massaged the duck egg mash on the green pasture.  Juxtaposition, hitherto
unrealistic, was accomplished.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sir, I flipped the Dosa, and waited for the other side to get cooked, flipped it
again, and kept the Dosa aside. Made one more Dosa like that, sir. Later, I ate
both Dosas with Maple syrup, Chammanthi Podi, and Coin pappads sir.  
Sync sir, Unbelievable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;What is a Chammanthi podi?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Sir, this is not the appropriate time sir. Maybe later.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Then?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I had a pear, drank 350ml of water, brushed my teeth, wrote a blog post, washed
my legs, and went to bed. I continued reading the book "To kill a mockingbird",
when suddenly heard a loud noise from outside sir.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Is that it?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yes sir.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Well, write down your address and phone number. You will have to come to the&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;police station when called upon, to give your statement about yesterday's&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;incident.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Done deal sir. Many peace.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Kindly leave your feedback &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mind_toilet/status/1308332694489587714?s=20"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>comedy</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/crime-scene/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 17:30:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Misogynist married a feminist</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/misogynist-married-a-feminist/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The sky was clear and the occasion was auspicious, all set to witness the unwitnessed. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The Misogynist-Feminist wedding!&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The cool breeze from the east moved her jet black hair to his teeth.
He stopped grinning at once. 
No one was invited to their wedding, yet they were facing a sea of 
willing crowd to this fictional reality. When the news was whispered 
to them on a hot summer day, they were all &lt;i&gt;thunderstruck&lt;/i&gt;, 
and screamed in unison, "What the"!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The ceremony began with frowns. The crowd murmured incessantly.  They argued the
male was feminist, and female misogynist; said it was a marriage made in paradox
not paradise.  When the couple vowed to make each other successful, old women in
the crowd lifted their hands to mouth in pure shock.  Maybe, the crowd was not
ready for this, it was way ahead of their time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Meanwhile, the &lt;i&gt;Cardinals of language&lt;/i&gt; convened in a brand new library.
&lt;i&gt;Grammar goons&lt;/i&gt; waited outside with safety pins and clown hats.  They were angry
at the innate irony of the scheme, thought it to be a joke; their honor and
semantics being dragged through mud. A lesson must be taught.  The infidels
should be ostracized from dictionaries at the least. At last, the convention
decided to punish them with the &lt;i&gt;punishment-that-shall-never-be-given&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A huge drama followed, and the couple lived happily ever-after.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Kindly leave your feedback &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mind_toilet/status/1308332118699683842?s=20"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>satire</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/misogynist-married-a-feminist/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 17:04:27 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>