<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>mindtoilet (Posts about dosa)</title><link>https://mindtoilet.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://mindtoilet.github.io/categories/dosa.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com"&gt;mind&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 23:52:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Crime scene</title><link>https://mindtoilet.github.io/posts/crime-scene/</link><dc:creator>mind</dc:creator><description>&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;What happened?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I was reading a book, and suddenly heard a loud noise from outside.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Can you please elaborate?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That's what sir, BANG!, and seconds later, a second BANG.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Will you be able to recreate your evening till the incident?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Yes, sir. Yesterday I came back late from work, to attend two more late evening&lt;br&gt;
meetings. Ms. Elusive Luck's birthday, &lt;b&gt;my god&lt;/b&gt;, both meetings got cancelled&lt;br&gt;
at my arrival. So, I practised music for what I thought was an hour.&lt;br&gt;
Sir, It was a good workout, and by the end I was sweating and shivering&lt;br&gt;
from forehead to heels. I wrapped the set, and was hungrily wandering indoors.&lt;br&gt;
That's when i saw the most beautiful thing on my study table. A banana!&lt;br&gt;
Who keeps a banana on a study table, sir? Well, I did, yesterday morning.&lt;br&gt;
Sync sir, Unbelievable.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Alright, then what?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sir, i thought of cooking dinner. Dosa in my mind, I found couple of duck eggs&lt;br&gt;
in the fridge. 'Egg Dosa' creeped, sorry, crept into my head. I fetched Dosa&lt;br&gt;
batter and eggs to the warmth outside. Roasted some curry leaves, and ground&lt;br&gt;
them with chillies into a lush green paste. Fried some Coin Pappads as well.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
An eerie silence lurked in the kitchen while I was chopping onions. I added&lt;br&gt;
salt, and a pinch of turmeric to the onions. Then I introduced our dear eggs&lt;br&gt;
to Madame la Guillotine, CRACK!, its viscous yellow head crashed into the bowl.&lt;br&gt;
I stirred a motley mixture with all that. When the pan on the stove, started&lt;br&gt;
whispering to the winds, i threw a water blanket over it. The pan hissed,&lt;br&gt;
and shot sodium-in-water sorta tantrums at me. I calmly slid the hot bubbling&lt;br&gt;
bubbles into the sink. Then, I painted a solar system on the pan with batter.&lt;br&gt;
The system had to be perfect. A subtle press in the center was by followed by&lt;br&gt;
concentric Sufi whirling. It must spread into a round Gaussian distribution,&lt;br&gt;
and scatter a Brownian motion of batter pores. The pores would channel the&lt;br&gt;
steam upwards, cooking the layers above en route its itinerary. Then, i&lt;br&gt;
sprayed oil, and smeared the lush green paste on top of the maturing Dosa.&lt;br&gt;
Few seconds later, I massaged the duck egg mash on the green pasture.&lt;br&gt;
Juxtaposition, hitherto unrealistic, was accomplished.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sir, I flipped the Dosa, and waited for the other side to get cooked, flipped it&lt;br&gt;
again, and kept the Dosa aside. Made one more Dosa like that, sir. Later, I ate&lt;br&gt;
both Dosas with Maple syrup, Chammanthi Podi, and Coin pappads sir.&lt;br&gt;
Sync sir, Unbelievable.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;What is a Chammanthi podi?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sir, this ain't the appropriate time sir. Maybe later.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Then?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I had a pear, drank 350ml of water, brushed my teeth, wrote a blog post, washed&lt;br&gt;
my legs, and went to bed. I continued reading the book "To kill a mockingbird",&lt;br&gt;
when suddenly heard a loud noise from outside sir.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Is that it?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yes sir.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Well, write down your address and phone number. You will have to come to the&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;police station when called upon, to give your statement about yesterday's&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;incident.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Done deal, sir. Many peace.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>cooking</category><category>crime</category><category>dosa</category><category>food</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.github.io/posts/crime-scene/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 17:30:56 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>