<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>mindtoilet (Posts about football liverpoolfc Palakkad Kerala)</title><link>https://mindtoilet.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://mindtoilet.github.io/categories/football-liverpoolfc-palakkad-kerala.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com"&gt;mind&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 23:52:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>A football dream</title><link>https://mindtoilet.github.io/posts/a-football-dream/</link><dc:creator>mind</dc:creator><description>&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Liverpool FC is my football club. Palakkad is a beautiful town in Kerala,&lt;br&gt;
India.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have a dream…&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Liverpool FC came to Palakkad to play a football game. Sadio Mane was on the&lt;br&gt;
bench, but he chose to stand with the fans. While watching the game, standing&lt;br&gt;
next to him was a confident young man. Naturally, they became friends.&lt;br&gt;
Unforeseen, as is usually the case with nature, the game was cancelled few&lt;br&gt;
minutes into the it for a reason I cannot recall.  I asked Sadio, “Will you&lt;br&gt;
play football with us in my school?“ He said yes.  So I took him to Navodaya&lt;br&gt;
Vidyalaya, Palakkad, the best school in the world.  I introduced Sadio to my&lt;br&gt;
friends and they all were ready for a game.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://mindtoilet.github.io/galleries/NavodayaGround.JPG" alt="nil"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
The moment Sadio saw the ground, he fell in love with it. Western ghats in the&lt;br&gt;
backdrop and the amazing Palakkadan wind made him say: “This is where I should&lt;br&gt;
be playing”. Sadio played in my attack and I played in the midfield. When my&lt;br&gt;
goalkeeper passed me a short ball, I looked up the field and saw Sadio making&lt;br&gt;
the run. With my barefoot, I sliced the ball and it was airborne. Seconds later,&lt;br&gt;
that touch by Sadio and the finish, the ball was in the back of the net.  The&lt;br&gt;
trend continued, he made those runs and I sent him through on the goal. We won!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
After the post match handshake and hug, Sadio asked me: “Why don’t you come to&lt;br&gt;
Melwood some day?” in French obviously. I smiled, and said “Oui, I will&lt;br&gt;
try. Merci beaucoup”.  Sadio flew back to England, in the plane he spoke to a&lt;br&gt;
man called Jurgen Klopp. Mr. Klopp spoke to someone, and a week later I got&lt;br&gt;
a call from Liverpool FC, the best football club in the world.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I landed in John Lennon airport. Imagine all the people, waiting for me.  I&lt;br&gt;
reached Melwood, Liverpool FC's training ground, where my accommodation was&lt;br&gt;
arranged. Sadio introduced me to his friends. Virgil was taller than me. Trent&lt;br&gt;
is younger than me. Robbo warned me about Millie's humour sense. Mo's English&lt;br&gt;
was better than mine. I gave Ali a chocolate and he kept it. I told Bobby he is&lt;br&gt;
my favourite player. The boss gave me hug and said welcome. I knew I was home.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I wore my boots for evening's training session. Sadio told Jurgen that he wanted&lt;br&gt;
me to play in his side. I scored one, assisted two, made a goal saving tackle and&lt;br&gt;
broke my ankle. Hendo lifted the ball onto Mo's path, cut it back to Bobby, he&lt;br&gt;
did a no-look flick into the empty space behind Virgil. I was too quick for Big&lt;br&gt;
Virgil. Blink of an eye, I slotted it past Adrian. I copied Bobby's celebration.&lt;br&gt;
Allison played a simple ball to me, I looked up the field and saw Sadio making&lt;br&gt;
the run. I sliced the ball and it was airborne. Seconds later, that touch by&lt;br&gt;
Sadio and the finish, the ball was in the back of the net. The second assist&lt;br&gt;
followed a neat link up play between Bobby, Mo, Sadio and Me. Bobby's no look&lt;br&gt;
finish met my cross at the far post. Jurgen's celebration to that was wild.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I might have kicked the wall too hard. That's how I woke up with a broken ankle,&lt;br&gt;
but it was definitely worth the dream.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
YWNA!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>football liverpoolfc Palakkad Kerala</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.github.io/posts/a-football-dream/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 21:15:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>