<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VINODH'S NOTES (Posts about language)</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://vinotes.github.io/categories/language.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2024 &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com"&gt;Vinodh MJ Human&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 01:10:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>They/Them</title><link>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/theythem/</link><dc:creator>Vinodh MJ Human</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Pronouns replace a person's name in a sentence. They/Them are pronouns attached
to human beings who identify differently from He/Him or She/Her, the
conventional Male or Female. The application of these words are predominantly in
the English language used in North America, Europe, and Australia. This has
created some debate owing to the singular/plural usage of They/Them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Examples: "Tell them to take care."
"What are they doing?"
"Did they have any food?"
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In all of the above sentences, they/them could be interpreted as either singular
or plural. Apparently, native English speakers could convincingly deploy such
usage without causing any confusion. Non-native speakers on the contrary usually
learn English language from grammar books; which explains the syntax and
semantics of they/them to be used as plural to other pronouns. English, even
though the most popular language in the world, lacks an agreed structure. You
might have noticed that what you pronounce is not always what you write. Same
word could morph into a different meaning in a different context. I am not an
expert, but these anomalies are easily noticed by a non-native speaker. Anyway,
the argument is about They/Them and its validity.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the core of it, living in a society demands interactions with fellow human
beings. If we were to live in caves, as we used to, then pronouns wouldn't have
mattered much. But now, as a collective, we are past that stage of
civilisation. Of course there is always a war, lack of basic amenities to a
large proportion of population, novel diseases, climate change, and other
crisis, etc., but those are macro-issues. Language on the other hand is
day-to-day, it impact our interactions with our real friends, social media
friends, colleagues, colleagues, and every other person you meet. It is the
fabric of a society. It has continuously evolved, and has been improved,
criticised, adapted over the centuries, and will continue to do so.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>language</category><category>politics</category><category>society</category><guid>https://vinotes.github.io/posts/theythem/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 20:59:20 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>