<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>mindtoilet (Posts about nature)</title><link>https://mindtoilet.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://mindtoilet.github.io/categories/nature.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com"&gt;mind&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 20:56:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mighty mountains</title><link>https://mindtoilet.github.io/posts/mighty-mountains/</link><dc:creator>mind</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://mindtoilet.github.io/galleries/dhanteras.JPG" alt="nil"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Mighty mountains, I dreaded its peaks and curves,&lt;br&gt;
But the spirit indomitable inside, settled my nerves.&lt;br&gt;
So, I climbed and climbed to the top,&lt;br&gt;
leaving behind my past; I did not stop.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
First came the rain, making my feet wet,&lt;br&gt;
then came the sun, making my brow sweat.&lt;br&gt;
I crossed a line that made the trees jealous,&lt;br&gt;
Pain building in my body, but I could not care less.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My mind must make that crucial decision,&lt;br&gt;
which stone to tread on next in this expedition.&lt;br&gt;
For choosing the wrong step could be as fatal,&lt;br&gt;
as living a life, without an adventure to tell.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Alas, I saw my yellow tent by the riverside,&lt;br&gt;
On a valley alike a silver necklace on a bride.&lt;br&gt;
Stretched my shape, and washed my face,&lt;br&gt;
with water so cold that set my wits ablaze.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Twilight flirted with day and night,&lt;br&gt;
Sky blushed as it turned orange, bright.&lt;br&gt;
Adios, I am done for the day, said the setting Sun.&lt;br&gt;
'See you on the other side' was Earth's cunning pun.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The river carried mountain's letter to the sea.&lt;br&gt;
The poem rhymed words of passionate love to me.&lt;br&gt;
Fate, they cannot unite; divided by an invisible wall.&lt;br&gt;
Faith! the mountain still awaited the next rainfall.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Have you been waiting for something all your life?&lt;br&gt;
I walked in the dark for long, forlorn, with an inner strife.&lt;br&gt;
Then I stopped and looked up, now the canvas was painted black;&lt;br&gt;
An imperial white moon and a thousand splendid suns smiled back.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>Himalayas</category><category>mountains</category><category>nature</category><category>night</category><category>river</category><category>sea</category><category>sky</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.github.io/posts/mighty-mountains/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 20:27:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>