<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mindtoilet (Posts about poem)</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://mindtoilet.com/categories/poem.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2025 &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com"&gt;mindtoilet&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 20:52:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Curses and Chances</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/cursesandchances/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The curse is upon all of us.&lt;br&gt;
But we are not at faults!&lt;br&gt;
To collect thoughts and connect dots.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Curse of love, my love,&lt;br&gt;
Curse of care, brother,&lt;br&gt;
Curse of bond, my friend,&lt;br&gt;
Blood, kin, and beyond.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But, for every curse, there is a chance,&lt;br&gt;
That might seem second at first,&lt;br&gt;
but for a lifetime it will stick with us,&lt;br&gt;
Only if we embrace it at self behest,&lt;br&gt;
Alike the tale of hare and tortoise.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Hitherto, we lived in parallel lines,&lt;br&gt;
Belated, your smile crossed mine.&lt;br&gt;
Then we spoke, and we laughed,&lt;br&gt;
And then we sang, and we danced.&lt;br&gt;
We are thus aware that we were,&lt;br&gt;
For our purpose, joie de vivre!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There are only poems, no poets,&lt;br&gt;
Art owns its own artist.&lt;br&gt;
A deaf maestro's lullaby,&lt;br&gt;
That we could finally,&lt;br&gt;
Feel the friend in you and me,&lt;br&gt;
Where serendipity serenades to our vivacious youth,&lt;br&gt;
And the greatest relief lies in telling the truth.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/cursesandchances/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 15:59:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Love</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/love/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
How can it be put into words?&lt;br&gt;
For love itself is just a word, borrowed.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/love/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 23:15:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A story unsaid</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/a-story-unsaid/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The night, soothingly quiet, our poet awoke in her bed.&lt;br&gt;
Eyes wide, a story unsaid, raging in her head.&lt;br&gt;
She opened her book and started scribbling away,&lt;br&gt;
Hoping that the memory of her dream would stay.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Lying on a hammock she thought,&lt;br&gt;
About a piquant dream she caught.&lt;br&gt;
A story unsaid that she must tell,&lt;br&gt;
Out of her mind, before it fell.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There was the familiar little girl,&lt;br&gt;
Who wore a necklace made of pearl.&lt;br&gt;
Ah..! that curious world inside a crystal bowl,&lt;br&gt;
And indeed the villain who resembled her brother Paul.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Enter villain with an orange balloon in his hand,&lt;br&gt;
Three feet tall, skinny lad was all tanned.&lt;br&gt;
With him he always brought his own music band,&lt;br&gt;
Popular songs they played were all banned.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The orange balloon hovered over his head like a halo,&lt;br&gt;
Her eyes twinkled as she went to say hello.&lt;br&gt;
Will you give me that orange balloon I crave?&lt;br&gt;
Quid pro quo, young lady, he said with a smile, suave.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Shake hands with me for it, little doll?&lt;br&gt;
No, you'll squeeze my fingers like a troll.&lt;br&gt;
Sing a song about Tweedledum but not Tweedledee?&lt;br&gt;
Its impossible! How dare you demand such a deed?&lt;br&gt;
The pearl necklace then, yes?&lt;br&gt;
Oh, no, villains can't have necklaces.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
How right you are, here, take it my friend.&lt;br&gt;
Ha-ha, I know, villains always lose in the end.&lt;br&gt;
As she reached out for the balloon, he let it fly,&lt;br&gt;
Ha-ha, where's the fun in not letting it touch the sky?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
She woke up with a start, still lying on the hammock,&lt;br&gt;
The pearl necklace was planted safely on her neck.&lt;br&gt;
She opened her book and started scribbling away,&lt;br&gt;
Hoping that the memory of her dream would stay.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The night, soothingly quiet, is coming to its end,&lt;br&gt;
The poet stood in the balcony facing a sea and beyond.&lt;br&gt;
Words on her book rhymed, pearls on her neck shined,&lt;br&gt;
An orange balloon dawned up in the sky and she smiled.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;
poem by &lt;span class="underline"&gt;&lt;i&gt;O. S. Toelyn&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/a-story-unsaid/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>City Rain</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/cityrain/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Like an ancient civilization, the city slept,&lt;br&gt;
In an endless commute, its way of life wept.&lt;br&gt;
In mirky buildings and sulky streets,&lt;br&gt;
Boredom grumbled and happiness crumbled.&lt;br&gt;
Hither and yon people ran to make ends meet,&lt;br&gt;
And that's when the first drop of rain came to greet.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
His highness's arrival was announced by Dhol drums,&lt;br&gt;
Boisterous, it lifted the city out of its doldrums.&lt;br&gt;
Bewitched the wind into a wicked poltergeist,&lt;br&gt;
Which possessed the poor trees at first.&lt;br&gt;
Made them dance with no rhyme, nor reason,&lt;br&gt;
The city was under its spell in a summer season.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, across the tar road, he boarded a bus, red,&lt;br&gt;
Sitting by a window, he peered outside - mayhem manifested.&lt;br&gt;
Citizens with books, bags, and sarees over their head,&lt;br&gt;
Steam rising from a packed tea shop in the distance, ahead,&lt;br&gt;
A woman wrestling with nature to ignite a cigarette,&lt;br&gt;
He shared a laugh with nature at this singular etiquette.&lt;br&gt;
An umbrella afloat, weightless in a whirlwind,&lt;br&gt;
A fine mocking at humankind failing to take the hint.&lt;br&gt;
The rain gained momentum as the bus coughed forward,&lt;br&gt;
He looked behind and saw memories travelling backwards.&lt;br&gt;
As he closed his eyes, a downpour of nostalgia deluged his face,&lt;br&gt;
A boy buoyant in his village pond, droplets of euphoria in his gaze.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, she picked up the book, her precious company,&lt;br&gt;
The wooden arm chair beckoned her from the spacious balcony.&lt;br&gt;
Feet up on the chair, rocking back and forth,&lt;br&gt;
She witnessed sky coalesce with the earth.&lt;br&gt;
A deep breath flooded her heart with petrichor,&lt;br&gt;
The open book capsized her brain vessels in bibliochor.&lt;br&gt;
For once, her heart and brain agreed,&lt;br&gt;
Knowledge is the purpose of her life ahead.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, they said, let's keep playing,&lt;br&gt;
This can't get any better, keep the ball rolling.&lt;br&gt;
The rain couldn't drench their jerseys wet,&lt;br&gt;
For they were already saturated in sweat.&lt;br&gt;
Raindrops across flood lights was quite the sight,&lt;br&gt;
A special game, they must win this with all their might.&lt;br&gt;
A hot shower, a biryani, awaits, and perhaps a drive into the night,&lt;br&gt;
Where the city shines bright, and grows young until the first light.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, he sought her presence,&lt;br&gt;
She was not found inside their residence.&lt;br&gt;
He stared at the flight of stairs,&lt;br&gt;
A hop, skip, and a jump to the terrace.&lt;br&gt;
There she stood staring at the sky,&lt;br&gt;
Palms open, her hands lifted shoulder high.&lt;br&gt;
She wore pink clothes soaked from head-to-toe,&lt;br&gt;
He moved closer and hugged her apropos.&lt;br&gt;
She stepped on his feet, he kissed on top of her head,&lt;br&gt;
Shivering hands wrapped around his chest, her face rested.&lt;br&gt;
In that chilling juxtaposition they stood in silence,&lt;br&gt;
Under the rain they melded to a timeless ambience.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At the first drop, our poet slid into the kitchen,&lt;br&gt;
A cup of tea with a hint of mint and lemon.&lt;br&gt;
The curtains swung over the library irking the shadows,&lt;br&gt;
A venerable fountain pen lay on the table in its repose.&lt;br&gt;
The pen kissed the paper, then and back again,&lt;br&gt;
Until poet read the words, "City Rain".&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/cityrain/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 15:59:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>You Will Never Walk Alone!</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/ynwa/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
For a lifelong Liverpool F.C fan, this is the perfect gift.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I found a poem inside it. My friend Harish, a proud Chelsea F.C fan wrote this&lt;br&gt;
poem. He understands football better than anyone else. Football is mostly&lt;br&gt;
happiness, sometimes sorrow, triumphs and heartbreaks. It is freedom. It is a&lt;br&gt;
religion without animosity. We all love the game and the game loves us&lt;br&gt;
back. Football is love!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://mindtoilet.com/galleries/stevie.jpg" alt="nil"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Do you remember? Is it a blur? Reminisce,&lt;br&gt;
As you sailed through the highs and the lows,&lt;br&gt;
Through the soaring peaks and the infinte abyss,&lt;br&gt;
Darkness, the roll of a dice, chaos, the fall of a domino.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The words of a special anthem echoes&lt;br&gt;
Softly, just like it did in Turkey and Madrid&lt;br&gt;
A wave of red, devoured the green meadows&lt;br&gt;
Millions of souls dreamt, breathless, achieve it they did!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That echo is now a roar, your ears hurt&lt;br&gt;
Do not resist, for it is a beacon of hope&lt;br&gt;
Pull up your socks, be ready and be alert&lt;br&gt;
For even in the face of defeat, you will kop(e)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The walk is now a jog, the road to salvation&lt;br&gt;
The time to show how much you've grown&lt;br&gt;
A fallen tear, broken heart, a whisper, a realisation&lt;br&gt;
For even in lucid dreams, you'll never walk alone.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
by &lt;i&gt;Harish Ramachandran&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
YNWA!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>football</category><category>poem</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/ynwa/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:50:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mighty Mountains</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/mighty-mountains/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Mighty mountains,&lt;br&gt;
I saw its curves and peaks yonder,&lt;br&gt;
White clouds and blue skies surrounded.&lt;br&gt;
Usual voices inside, as I climb to the top,&lt;br&gt;
Iffy paths or dicey end, I shall not stop.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
First came the rain, making my feet wet,&lt;br&gt;
Then came the sun, making my brow sweat.&lt;br&gt;
Pain feasting on my body, but I couldn't care less,&lt;br&gt;
There, I crossed a line, that made the trees jealous.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Slippery stones and bottomless slope, flanking.&lt;br&gt;
Clinging mud and flatulent shoes, wringing.&lt;br&gt;
Looking back, a rucksack, reluctant,&lt;br&gt;
Looking ahead, a view, so magnificent.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And my mind must decide quick,&lt;br&gt;
For each step in this trek is a trick.&lt;br&gt;
A clumsy choice could be fatal,&lt;br&gt;
As a life without a tale to retell.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Alas, I reached the snow capped summit,&lt;br&gt;
Oh, the joy you get when you truly commit.&lt;br&gt;
White clouds and blue skies, singing sweet welcome,&lt;br&gt;
Jolly wind, like your pet, dancing as you get home.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sat by a yellow tent, I surveyed far and wide,&lt;br&gt;
Leaving its nest was a waterfall to my side,&lt;br&gt;
Chasing its petulant river-child running away,&lt;br&gt;
Is when the poet in me awoke to have a say.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Twilight now flirted with day and night,&lt;br&gt;
Sky blushed as it turned orange, bright.&lt;br&gt;
Adios, I am done for the day, said the setting Sun.&lt;br&gt;
'See you on the other side', was Earth's cunning pun.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The river carried mountain's letter to the sea.&lt;br&gt;
The poem rhymed words of passionate love to me.&lt;br&gt;
Fate, they cannot unite; kept apart by an invisible wall.&lt;br&gt;
Faith! the mountain always awaited the next rainfall.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I looked up, now the canvas was painted black,&lt;br&gt;
A full moon and a thousand splendid suns smiled back.&lt;br&gt;
I walked for long, forlorn, mind full of peace.&lt;br&gt;
Mighty mountains, I loved its curves and peaks.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;
poem by &lt;span class="underline"&gt;&lt;i&gt;O. S. Toelyn&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/mighty-mountains/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 20:27:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>