<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mindtoilet (Posts about review)</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://mindtoilet.com/categories/review.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2025 &lt;a href="mailto:mindtoilet@gmail.com"&gt;mindtoilet&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 14:11:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Chemeen - book review</title><link>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/chemeen-review/</link><dc:creator>mindtoilet</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Thakazhi has awarded a free pass into the theme park of his characters' minds;
to embark on its topsy-turvy rides one at a time. An allowance is issued to
trespass deep into their emotions without prosecution, to stay abreast with
their feelings of existence, ambition, conformity, judgement, justification, and
finally acceptance. You are cajoled into forgetting self and the author. At no
point is one invited to project their own sensory experiences of joy and plight
to that of any character, nor is asked to care about author's circumstances or
intentions. Death of the author, and oddly enough, also of the reader is
registered. One subconsciously melds into a seaside belonging to Karuthamma, the
protagonist, Chakki, her mother, Chembankunju, her father, Pareekutty, her
lover, Palani, her husband, and their individual soliloquies.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is no question of right and wrong, everyone is so, and so perhaps everyone
is wrong. One would certainly be defiant in attempting to distance from that
premise, for it might upset our convenience to earmark a villain at the outset.
There isn't a conspicuous one in this story. In essence, love is punished, by
forces invisible - of collective unconscious, orthodoxy, taboo, customs, fear,
righteousness, ambition, gossips, jealousy, helplessness, debt, law of the land,
and ultimately the person inside you.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Karuthamma and Pareekutty grew up as childhood mates in a coastal village
unbeknownst to each other that they were to be separated when they get older.
Their love was that of the permanent nest made in each other's mind, and of the
words exchanged and laughter shared. In their life they never touch each other.
Yet he was ruined and she was blamed for existence. Why were they deemed guilty?
Were they deserving of such a verdict? Of course they were guilty of living rent
free in each other's heads, which also belonged to their family and the
community. There is a tax to be paid on thoughts, especially if one is thinking
of love. Even more important was the hubris, their negligence, towards the
supernatural, to their belief in traditions and the omnipresent deity of
uncertainties, the &lt;i&gt;'Kadalamma'&lt;/i&gt;, the mother of the ocean. Everyone in that
community has had given a tacit consent at birth to be owned by the ocean and
the community they were born into, to its customs and rules. Being unamenable to
those benchmarks forges one into an accused, self-accused, implicit criminal of
invisible thought crimes, of which one cannot be absolved. Such a deed makes one
a bounty, a prey, a victim!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One is informed about the ambitious and avaricious father, the astute and
confused mother, and the strong helpless husband. The tragedy manifests in the
realisation that one cannot escape the bond of blood, as much as there is no
escape from the bond of &lt;i&gt;'anuragam'&lt;/i&gt; (love); eternally bound by those, in the
most cruel, sadomasochist manner, where you constantly reinforce your own
conviction of being at fault - your life is a burden to others, your love
disrupts peace. Once committed, knowingly or otherwise, there is no redemption,
because it transforms you into your own torturer, to become your own judge,
jury and executioner.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But eventually all that will disappear from memory for a timeless melody and an
everlasting embrace. By its own inimitable, inexplicable ways, love always
triumphs! When Pareekutty sings his heart out, Kaurthamma will always walk
towards him with the unadulterated clarity and perfect equanimity of mind. That
attraction, like everything else, is also beyond her control, perhaps aligning
with the laws of nature, subduing the ensuing repercussions, whatever the price
may be for that tryst, even if permanent solitude, love triumphs!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>review</category><guid>https://mindtoilet.com/posts/chemeen-review/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:00:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>